好 我们开始吧
Okay, let's begin.
谁想先说?
Who wants to start?
好 布兰妮 你先说
Yes, Brittany, kick it off.
我对文本没有想法
I don't have a thought on the reading,
我只是对白板上的词有意见
I just think that that word on the board is wrong.
《人造黑鬼》  弗兰纳里·奥康纳著
我满确定"黑鬼"没有写错
Well, I think it still has two G's in it last I checked.
这并不好笑
It's not funny.
我们不该成天盯着"黒鬼"一词看
We shouldn't have to stare at the N-word all day.
听着
Uh, listen,
这是一门关于美国南方的文学课
this is a class on the literature of the American south.
你们会遇到老套的思想和粗俗的语言
You're going to encounter some archaic thoughts, coarse language,
但大家都是成年人 相信你们可以理解
but we're all adults here and I think we can understand it
这些作品的背景脉络
within the context in which it's written.
我只是认为那个词很冒犯人
Well, I just find that word really offensive.
恕我直言 布兰妮
With all due respect, Brittany,
连我都不在意了 我相信你也可以
I got over it, I'm pretty sure you can too.
没必要吧
Well, I don't see why.
好吧
Right.
好 还有人对文本有别的想法吗?
Now, does anyone else have any thoughts on the reading?
这让你的某些学生感到不舒服
Well, it made some of your students uncomfortable.
他们何时变得如此脆弱?
When did they all become so goddamn delicate?
那并不是单一事件  -什么?
This wasn't an isolated incident. What?
上个月 你问某个学生  他家人是否曾是纳粹
Last month you asked a student if his family had been Nazis.
我的确有这么做 他是德国人啊
Yeah, I did, he's German,
我们当时在读《反美阴谋》
we were reading The Plot Against America
相信我 看他坐立不安的样子  他家人一定是
and trust me, by the way he was squirming, they were.
老天啊
Oh, my God.
莫克 你是位才华洋溢的作家  我们很荣幸能聘请你来
Um, Monk, you are a very talented writer, we're fortunate to have you here.
什么?   -他有好几年没出书了
What? He hasn't published in years.
从你上次出书后  我已经写了三本小说
I have written three novels since the last time you published.
你说得没错 而你写作的速度
Yeah, this is true, and the speed with which you write
再次证明好事多磨
only proves that good things take time.
去死啦 莫克  -别激动 曼帝
Oh, go to hell, Monk.  -Relax, Mandy.
对啊 别激动 曼帝
Yeah, relax, Mandy.
总之 我的新书会由回音出版社出书
And anyway, my new book is with Echo
我的经纪人说他们非常期待
and my agent says they're very excited about it.
真是令人开心的消息
Oh, that's great to hear.
那本书在讲什么?   -别再拖了 李奥?
What's it about?  -Can we stop stalling, Leo?
听着 莫克
Listen, Monk,
我们希望你能休息一阵子
we'd like to give you a break.
"休息"是什么意思?   -去放个假吧
What do you mean, break? Just some time off.
强制放假
Mandatory time off.
反正你也要去波士顿  参加读书节 不是吗?
It's just, you're already going to Boston for the festival, right?
你何不待久一点?   -因为我恨波士顿 我老家就在那里
Why don't you just stay there for--Because I hate Boston, my family's there.
你需要放松 你太紧绷了 老兄
Well, you need some time to relax. You're on edge, man.
你以为跟家人相处
You're under the impression that time spent
就能让压力消失吗?
with my family will take the edge off.
我没事  -才怪
I'm fine.  -You're not fine.
我上周看到你在车里哭  他还揍了方向盘
I saw you crying in your car last week. He punched the steering wheel.
哇 若你少花点时间监视我
Oh, wow. You know, if you spent less time spying on me,
你也许可以多写一打书
you could probably write a dozen more novels
放在机场跟那些颈枕和饼干一起卖
that people buy at airports with their neck pillows and Cheez-Its.
你走心了 要杠上了吗 烂人?
Oh, here we go. Okay. You want to go, dirty doggy?
好 祝你在波士顿玩得开心
Okay, well, enjoy Boston.
你可以去机场买我的书
You can... you can get my book at the airport.
也祝你跟回音合作愉快
Oh, and, good luck with Echo.
You turned my house
Into a home
You made me feel love
I'm not alone
And unafraid
Yeah
Of time to come
Proved...
Then you taught me how
What it means
Can we wake Each and
every morning Inside a dream?
美国小说
喂?
Hello?
欢迎回来 回家的感觉如何?
Welcome back. How's it feel to be home?
很棒
Great.
已有穿着波士顿棕熊队运动衫的家伙  问我是否自以为高人一等?
Already had a guy in a Bruins jersey ask me if I think I'm better than him.
那代表好运
That's good luck here.
是波士顿版本的好运
That's Boston's version of a ladybug landing on you.
有什么新消息吗?
Any news?
回音的帕特里克不想要这本书  但谁在乎?
Patrick at Echo is passing. But who fucking cares?
他是个老酒鬼
He's an old alcoholic.
那是他拒绝的第九本书吗?
What is that? Nine now?  -He says,
他说："这本书写得不错
"This book is finely crafted
角色的发展完整 词汇丰富
with fully developed characters and rich language,
但我不懂他改写
but one is lost to understand what this reworking of
艾斯奇勒斯的《波斯人》  与非裔美国人的经验有何关联"
Aeschylus' The Persians has to do with the African-American experience?"
就是这样
There it is.
他们想要黑人的书  -他们已经有黑人的书
They want a Black book. They have a Black book.
我是黑人 这是我的书
I'm Black, and it's my book.
你懂我的意思
You know what I mean.
你是说他们要我写  关于警察杀死青少年
You mean they want me to write about a cop killing some teenager
或在多切斯特  抚养五个孩子的单亲妈妈
or a single mom in Dorchester raising five kids.
多切斯特现在已经很白了  但你说得没错
Dorchester is pretty white now. But yes.
老天 我根本不在乎种族
Jesus Christ. You know, I don't even really believe in race.
但问题是 其他人都很在乎
Yeah. The problem is that everyone else does.
总之 祝你读书节愉快
Anyway, have fun at the book festival.
千万不要侮辱任何重要人物
And just don't insult anyone important.
拜托
Please.
大众读书节  波士顿会议展览中心
从历史的观点写作  并不表示你不能写出
Writing from a historical perspective doesn't mean that you can't
与现代人有共鸣的作品
make work that doesn't resonate with today's audiences.
塞洛尼斯·艾里森
我认为对我们这些书呆子而言  《权力的游戏》证明了
Yeah, I think of things like Game of Thrones as proof that
这样的作品也能成功
nerds like us can still find great success.
很可惜的 今天的讨论只能到此为止
Unfortunately, we're going to have to end it there.
感谢作家和与会者们共襄盛举
Thank you to our authors and thanks to all of you for attending.
是我的错觉  还是这读书节场子真的很小?
Is it just me, or was this small even for a book festival?
是真的 因为我们在跟辛塔拉比场子
Yeah, it's because we're up against Sintara.
谁?
Who?
辛塔拉·戈登 你没读过她的书吗?
Sintara Golden. You haven't read her?
不知道 她写了什么书?
No, what's her book called?
(《咱们在贫民窟的日子》  辛塔拉·戈登著
这本书红遍天下 报章杂志争相报道
Raves everywhere. The Post, Bookforum.
《伦敦书评》评论
The London Review of Books said,
"《咱们在贫民窟的日子》  是部令人心碎又发自肺腑的处女作"
"We's Lives in Da Ghetto is a heartbreaking and visceral debut."
我也听说有电视剧要改编她的作品
Plus a little birdie told me that perhaps there's a TV adaptation in the works?
不予置评
No comment.
主要舞台
好吧 至少我试着问了
Okay, it was worth a shot.
你成为作家前的生活是什么样子呢?
Tell us, what was your life like before you were an author?
我在欧柏林读完大学后搬到纽约
Well, I did undergrad at Oberlin and moved to New York the day after graduation
毕业隔天我就搬了 几个月后
and a couple months later,
我在出版社当助理
I was an assistant at a publisher.
当助理的经验  是否影响了你日后的著作?
And did that assistant experience shape your writing?
当然 我是第一读者
Absolutely. Yeah, I was a first reader meaning
表示我会读完所有的稿子
I would read all the manuscripts in the slush pile
在一大叠稿子中挑出不错的作品
and send them up the ladder
继续往上送
if they were any good.
有些作品还不错  但大多稿子都差强人意
Some of them were great, most were not.
但有种感受令我难以忘怀
But the feeling I couldn't shake was that
就是无论那些书有多棒
no matter how good the books were,
大部分都是纽约的白人男作家写的
most every submission was from some white dude from New York
他们当时正在经历离婚
going through a divorce,
没什么作品是关于我的族群
and too few of them were about my people.
这让我思考："我们的故事呢? "
And so I think, "Where are our stories?"
"代表我们的著作在哪里? "
You know, "Where's our representation?"
正因为这种匮乏 我的书也随之诞生
And it was from that lack that my book was born.
能帮我们读一段你的作品摘录吗?
Would you give us the pleasure of reading an excerpt?
谢谢
Thank you.
"哟 莎兰德
"'Yo, Cheranda,
你这么匆忙要去哪里? "
where you be goin' in a hurry likes that?'
唐娜看我出门时问道
Donna aks me when she see me comin' out the house.
"不关你的事 但你想知道的话
'Ain't none ya business, but if'n you gots to know,
我要去药店"
I's goin' to the pharmacy.'
我回头往门口看我妈是否出来了
I looks back at the door to see if Mama comin' out.
"药店? 为什么? " 她问
'The pharmacy? What for?' she aks.
"你知道的" 我说
'You know', I says.
"才怪" 她说
'Nah', she say.
"不会吧 姑娘 你又怀孕了? "
'Hell, nah! Girl, you be pregnant again?'
"有可能" 我告诉她
'Might's be', I tells her.
"如果是真的话 这一次
'And if I is, Ray-Ray's gonna be a real father
小瑞真的要当爸了"
this time around.'"
谢谢
Thank you.
太棒了
Yes!
嗨  -嗨
Hi...  -Hi.
我要找莉莎·艾里森
I'm here to see Lisa Ellison.
你有挂号吗? 我们快关门了
Uh, do you have an appointment? We're about to close.
没有 我是她哥
No, I'm her brother.
她就在那里
There she is.
波士顿生殖中心
你好 莫克
Hello, Monk.
嗨 莉莎
Hi, Lisa.
你在船上 马达坏了
Okay, you're in a boat, the motor cuts out,
但水并不深
but you're in shallow water,
而你穿着非常昂贵的鞋子
but you're wearing $600 shoes, but...
但你前往机场的车
your ride to the airport
就要从沙滩上开走了
is just pulling away from the beach,
这会产生什么选择问题?
why, oh, why is this a legal issue?
不知道
I don't know.
你只能选鸡不可湿或机不可失
It's a matter of row versus wade.
老天
Oh, my God.
我觉得那是我最得意的笑话
I think that's one of my best.
哇
Wow.
好吧
Okay.
你何时又开始抽烟的?
When did you start smoking again?  -Mm...
离婚后
Right after the divorce.
我一直都很痛恨赖瑞
I always hated Larry.
我知道
Oh, I know.
我们交往时你就这么说了  你还记得我有多生气吗?
You told me right when we started dating. Do you remember how mad I got?
"我搞谁吹谁都不关你的事"
"It's not your business who I fuck! Who I fellate."
我才没说"吹"  -我以为你有
I definitely did not say "fellate." I thought you did.
总之那是我听到的意思
That's how I heard it anyway.
很高兴见到你
It's good to see you.
我也很高兴见到你
Yeah, it's good to see you too.
工作如何?
How's work?
不太光彩
It's not very glamorous.
我每天都得走过金属探测器
I go through a metal detector every day.
你的工作很重要  -这个嘛
Well, what you do is important. Well...
而我只能在脑中想象各种人物
Meanwhile, all I do is invent little people in my head,
并创造想象的对话
then make them have imaginary conversations with each other.
书本会改变人们的生命
Books change people's lives.
我写的东西改变过你的生命吗?
Did something I've written ever change your life?
当然有
Absolutely.
毫无疑问
我的餐桌本来很不稳
My dining room table was wobbly as hell before your last book came out.
老天 够了  -然后你出了新书
Oh, my God. All right.  -It was, like, perfect.
厚度实在太完美了  -老天
Yeah. Oh, God.  -I'm telling you and--
真的 太厉害了  -拜托送我回机场
Take me back to Logan, please.
机场也帮不上忙 莫克  -我的老天
Logan cannot help you, Monk. Oh, my God!
欢迎回家 宝贝
Welcome home, baby!
有人在吗?
Hello! Hello!
莫克先生  -罗兰
Mr. Monk!  -Lorraine!
你知道这样会让我很尴尬  叫我莫克就好
You know how that makes me feel. It's just Monk.
别这样
Oh, don't do that to me,
我年纪大了 记不住新名字了
you know I'm too old to learn new names.
你好吗 莉莎小姐?   -我很好
How you doing, Miss Lisa?  -I'm good.
你看起来很不错 莫克先生  -我变肥了
You look good, Mr. Monk.  -Oh, I look fat.
加州人才会这样说
Oh, that's the California talking.
若我带你去阿肯色州  你马上会变成选美皇后
I took you to Arkansas right now, you'd be a beauty queen.  -Ooh!
是我的小亲亲吗?   -太可怕了
Is that my Monkie?  -That's frightening.
嗨 妈
Hi, Mother.  -Oh.
你变肥了  -我知道
You look fat.  -Ah, I know.
准备去吃晚餐了吗 艾里森太太?
You ready to go to dinner, Mrs. Ellison?
我只要钱包和我的黑色开襟衫
Uh, I just need my purse and my black cardigan.
好的 我去拿
All right, I'll get it.
你还好吗?
Are you all right?  -Oh.
你每次心情不好的时候就会爆食
You overeat when you're depressed.
我没有心情不好
I'm not depressed,
我只是最近都没睡好
I've just been not sleeping well lately
也因此没有规律运动
and so, fell off my exercise routine.
坐吧  -所以你心情没有不好
-Here. So you're not depressed.
你只是有各种心情不好的症状
You just wear all the hallmarks of depression.
我很想你
I missed you.
赖瑞要来吗?
Is Larry coming?
没有 妈
No, Mother.
赖瑞跟我分开了 记得吗?
Larry and I are separated, remember?
我当然记得  -好
Of course, I remember.  -Okay.
我只是觉得他也能加入我们
I just thought he might join us.
看看你哥  -好吧
To see your brother. Okay.
有必要这样小题大做吗?
I mean, is it really such a big deal?
大家都会忘记事情
Everyone forgets things.
这并不表示她生病了
Doesn't mean she's sick necessarily.
人们都会忘记牙医约诊
People forget dentists' appointments.
她忘记我离婚了
She forgets I'm not married anymore.
太奇怪了
That's weird.
你觉得我们该怎么做?   -为什么是我要决定?
What do you suggest we do? Why do I have to decide?
因为你是医生  -你也是
Because you're a doctor.  -So are you.
我不是那种医生
I'm not that kind.
重点是 你是个聪明的成人
Okay, my point is, you are an intelligent adult.
我很厌倦成为她唯一的照顾者
And I'm tired of being the only person that takes care of her.
我不记得有人逼你这么做
Well, I don't recall anyone assigning you that responsibility.
是没有 但你和克里夫  马上就搬去西岸
No, you and Cliff just fled west as soon as you could
让我被迫成为唯一的照顾者
and left me as caretaker by default.
"我的工作在那里"  -对啦 "我的工作在那里"
My work's there.
我很遗憾 这让我无法
"My work's there." Yeah.  -Apologies that it prevents me
跟上家里发生的大小事情
from keeping up with the family melodrama.
就算你住在附近  你也不会知道发生了什么事
If you lived up the block, you wouldn't know what was going on.
我被困在这里照顾那间老房子
I'm stuck here taking care of that old house and finding
找出爸外遇的情书
love letters from Dad's affairs.
爸什么?   -爸外遇了
His what?  -His affairs.
你不知道他有外遇?
You didn't know he was having affairs?
不知道 你怎么知道的?
No. How did you?
他是位常旅行的妇科医生
Well, he was an OBGYN that was traveling constantly,
但他的病人都在波士顿
but his patients were in Boston.
他说他去参加会议
He said he was going to conferences.
他是去巡田水
He was making house calls.
我曾经看过他亲一位白人女人
Do you know that I saw him kiss a white woman
就在高中校园
in the park in high school?
有多白?   -这句话是什么意思?
How white? What do you mean, "How white?"
是贵妇白还是南波士顿白?
Like Brahmin white or Southie white.
谁知道啊 她的嘴唇很薄
I don't know. She had thin lips.
感觉接吻技术不太好
She looked like a bad kisser.
你有跟妈说吗?   -才没有
Did you tell Mother? No.
我才不要搞砸我们的生活
I wasn't going to blow up our lives.
她回来了 妈
She's coming back. Mom. Mom.
嗨
Hi.
你还好吗?
How you doing?
我们的女服务生没有穿内衣
Our waitress isn't wearing a bra.
好喔  -我没发现
Okay. I didn't notice.
看到这鬼东西了吗?   这东西能让我们离开贫民区
See this shit? This gonna take us out of the ghetto.
但这间房子有些规矩
But there are rules in the house.
第一 不准把产品放在屋里
Number one, never leave this product in the house.
第二 自己找你的员工
And number two, get your own crew.
第三 你的员工必须遵守纪律
Number three, got to have discipline in your crew.
第四 别太常夸奖黑鬼
Number four, don't praise a nigga too much.
不然他们会觉得你很软弱
Otherwise he's gonna think you're soft.
第五 不准示爱
Rule number five, don't show no love.
爱会害了你的命
Love will get you killed.
看到了吗? 就像是婊子一样
See this, it's like a bitch.
婊子是给你上 不是来上你的
You fuck a bitch, don't let a bitch fuck you.
你是男子汉吗? 那你谁都不需要
You're a man who don't need nothing.
没人可以伴你过漫漫长夜
No one will get you through.
这婊子? 这婊子会吸走你的魂
This bitch? This bitch will take your soul.
你们黑鬼没有家…
You niggas ain't got no fam...
神话、哲学
不好意思 尼德
Excuse me, uh, Ned.
你们有作家  塞洛尼斯·艾里森的书吗?
Do you have any books by the writer Thelonious Ellison?
有 在这边
Yeah, this way.
就在这里  -好的
Here you go.  -Right.
非裔美国人研究
Yeah.
等等 为什么这些书在这里?
Wait a minute, why are these books here?
我不知道
I'm not sure.
我只能猜作者艾里森是黑人
I would imagine that this author Ellison is... Black.
我就是艾里森  -嗯
That's me. Ellison. Yeah.
他就是我 我们都是黑人
He is me, and he and I are Black.
噢 我猜对了
Oh, bingo.
你没有猜对 尼德  这些书与非裔美国人研究
No bingo, Ned, these books have nothing to do with African-American studies,
毫无关联 它们只是文学作品
they're just literature.
这里最黑的东西是墨水
The blackest thing about this one is the ink.
书放哪一区不是我决定的
I don't decide what sections the books go in.
这里的工作人员都无法  连锁书店就是这样
No one here does. That's how chain stores work.
好吧 尼德
Right, Ned.
规矩不是你定的
You don't make the rules.
我会等你走之后再放回去
I'm just going to put them back after you leave.
你试试看啊 尼德
Don't you dare, Ned.
你给我试试看
Do not you dare.
尼德
Ned.
"大获成功"  "戈登的书就是好书"
莫克 你在干什么?
Monk, what are you doing?
妈妈的状况只会越来越糟
Mom's only going to get worse.
他们说脑力训练是有帮助的
They say mental exercise is good,
所以我才买那本园艺书给她
that's why I got her that gardening book.
种小黄瓜算脑力训练吗?
Does growing cucumbers count as mental exercise?
你这么做时真的很讨厌  -怎样?
I hate when you do that. What?
你通过问题来表达你的讥讽
You share your condescending opinion as a question
试图隐藏你的不屑
trying to disguise the condescension.
你为何不直接说你觉得园艺很蠢
Why don't you just say that you think that gardening is idiotic?
因为我并没有这样  -才怪
Uh, because that's not what I was doing.  -Bullshit.
也许我们可以找个看护  每周来几次
Maybe we can hire a nurse a few times a week.
谁要付看护的钱?   -你付不起吗?
Who's going to pay for that? You... you can't afford it?
离婚后就没办法了
Not after the divorce, I cannot.
虽然这样会让人心痛  但我们也许要卖掉海滩房
Well, it will hurt, but we'll probably have to sell the beach house.
我们确实必须卖掉那间海滩房
Yeah, we definitely need to sell the beach house,
但那笔钱是要用来还
but that money is going to go to pay back the reverse mortgage
妈另外一间房屋的反向抵押贷款
that our mother took out on the other house.
没错
Yeah.
我可以汇钱回来
Look, I can send some money home,
但不会太多 克里夫不能帮忙吗?
but it's not going to be much.  Can't Cliff chip in?
克里夫的状况不太好  -谁状况好了?
Cliff's not in a good place, okay? Who is? Okay?
莫克 贝卡夺走一切
Monk, Becca took everything.
他的孩子在学校被嘲笑
And the kids are getting teased at school.
我不知道  -这个嘛
I didn't know.  -Well...
也许你可以打电话给他
Maybe you should call him.
我很抱歉我一直都很疏远
I'm sorry I've always been so distant.
你也不是故意的
You couldn't help that.
你总是爸的最爱
You were always Dad's favorite.
那让克里夫和我感情比较好
And that made Cliff and I bond, and you resented us
这也导致你讨厌我们 所以…
for having that bond, and then...
你变得独来独往
I don't know, you just became self-sufficient.
我们从没谈过这样的事
You never talked about this.
我们从没谈过任何事
We never talked about anything.
很不可思议吗?
Is that surprising?
看看我们的父母
Look at our parents.
我唯一记得爸的情绪
The only emotions I remember from Dad...
就只有无聊跟暴怒
were boredom and rage.
无聊是一种情绪吗?
Is boredom an emotion?
又来了 字典侦探
Great. It's Detective Dictionary.
你很久没有这样称呼我了
You haven't called me that in forever.
老天
Oh, God!
怎么了?   -老天
What? Oh, come on!
别装了
-Oh, God!
莉莎? 你还好吗?
Lisa? You okay?
嘿
Hey.
嘿 救命！帮帮忙！
Hey, help! Help!
"若你正在读这封信 这表示我
"If you are reading this it's because I,
神奇的莉莎·艾里森
Lisa Magical Ellison...
已经过世了
have died.
当然 这种状况很糟
Obviously, this is not ideal...
但我想这种事总得发生
but I guess it had to happen at some point.
希望 我…
Hopefully, I...
希望我是被大汗淋漓的  伊卓瑞斯·艾巴
Hopefully, I expired under the heaving thrusts
猛烈地操爆而死
of a sweaty Idris Elba
或是更没尊严一点
or perhaps in a less dignified manner,
是被大汗淋漓的罗素·克洛操爆
under the heaving thrusts of a sweaty Russell Crowe."
无论我是怎么走的
"Irrespective of how I went,
我希望最亲近我的人
I ask that those closest to me...
不要为我太难过
not mourn all that much.
我过了自豪的人生
I lived a life that made me proud.
我有被爱着
I...I was loved...
也有回馈这样的爱
and I loved in return.
我找到让我有热情的工作
I found work that aroused my passions.
我相信我付出的比获得还多
I believe I gave more than I took.
我也尽我所能帮助别人
And I did my damnedest to help people in need.
除此之外  许多朋友都因为我年逾50
And on top of all that, many a friend wrongly accused me
还肌肤紧致 而胡乱控诉我
of having Botox because of how tight my skin
认为我有打波尿酸
stayed well into my 50's.
这种人生夫复何求?
What more could someone ask of a life?
我爱你们
I love you all.
谢谢你们今天来到这里
Thank you for being here today.
永别了
Goodbye.
莉莎敬上"
Lisa."
克里夫?
Cliff?
那是骨灰吗?
Are those human remains?
你们有得到许可吗?
You guys have a permit for that?
给我闭嘴 菲力普
Just shut the fuck up, Phillip.
克里夫 不准这样跟我说话
Cliff, you don't talk to me like that.
去你的 谁理你
Fuck you. I just did.
什么?   -你要我揍你一顿吗?
What?  -You want me to beat your ass?
我只是…  -给我滚
I'm just---Get the fuck out of here.
我要把你生吞活剥
I will eat your sweater vest for dinner.
不要  -混蛋 快滚
No--Yep.  -Bitch. Go. One.
我数到一  -给我滚 菲力普
Get the fuck out of here, Phillip.
二、三  -他总是这么讨人厌
I'm just---Two. Three.  -Always been a fucking douche.
大家都在哪里?
Where is everybody?
大家都累坏了
They're exhausted.
我有给罗兰助眠药
I gave Lorraine something to help her sleep.
妈在洗澡 我之后也会给她药
Mother's taking a bath. Then I'm going to dose her too.
晚点也可以给我吗?
You think maybe I can get some of that later tonight?
好啊 你睡不好吗?
Yeah. What, you're not sleeping well?
我通常都睡得不错 但最近不好
Normally, I sleep fine, but just lately.
了解
Yeah.
人们会习惯看到尸体吗?
Does seeing a dead body ever become normal?
不知道 我也没看过多少  -真的吗?
I don't know. I haven't seen many. Really?
我是整形医师
I'm a plastic surgeon.
若我看到尸体 那表示大事不妙了
If I'm looking at a corpse, then something went very awry.
也是
Right.
这让我替妈感到难过
Yeah. Made me feel for Mother.
很难想象当她发现爸过世的心情
Can't imagine what she must've gone through finding Dad...
是那样走的  -我懂
you know, like that. I know.
这么多死亡
So much death.
我们上回团聚在此是何时呢?
When was the last time we were here together?
也许十年前吧
Maybe ten years.
是啊
Yeah.
孩子们都还很小  -对
The kids were still little. Yeah.
对了 你的家人还好吗?
How is your family, by the way?
你在乎吗?
You actually care?
当然 不然我问你干什么?   你为何这么问?
Of course. Why would I ask? Why would you ask me that?
不知道 莫克 你不曾打来关心
I don't know, Monk. You never really called.
我很忙  -对 大家都很忙
I get busy.  -Yeah, everybody gets busy.
你疏离我们
You drift away.
你想知道我的家人如何?
You want to know how my family is?
我妻子因为发现我和别的男人  在床上而离开我
My wife left me 'cause she caught me in bed with a man.
她夺走了我的房子和一半的诊所
She took my house, half my practice.
我的孩子恨死我了
My kids fucking hate me.
我还住在该死的图森
And I still live in fucking Tucson.
图森怎么了?
What was wrong with Tucson?
老天 那里有一家同志酒吧
Oh, my God. There's one gay bar
里面都是大学生
and it's full of college kids.
有人问我是不是泰勒·派瑞
One of them asked me if I was Tyler Perry.
太糟了
That's terrible.
泰勒·派瑞住在亚特兰大
I mean, Tyler Perry lives in Atlanta, right?
去死啦
Fuck you, man.
闭嘴  -离图森那么远
Shut up. Nowhere near Tucson.
老天
Oh, boy.
你知道爸有外遇吗?
Did you know Dad had affairs?
当然
Oh, for sure.
怎么知道的?
How?
看就知道啊
You could just tell.
莉莎说她看过他亲一个白人女人
Lisa told me she saw him kissing a white woman once.
为什么我都不知道?
Why did I have no idea?
为什么我是最后知道的?
Why am I the last to know?
因为你太爱他了
Because you loved him too much.
敌人比朋友更了解彼此
Enemies see each other better than friends.
你给她吃什么?
What the hell did you give her?
止痛药 能让她们马上睡着
It's oxycodone. But knocks them right out.
你给她止痛药帮助睡眠?
You gave her opioids to sleep?
对啊 你看过嗑海洛因的人吗?
Yeah. You ever seen a heroin addict?
那些家伙站着就可以睡
Those guys take naps standing up.
太危险了
It's dangerous.
我会仔细观察她的 我是医生
Look, I'm keeping an eye on her. I'm a doctor.
我也是  -才怪
So am I.  -Right.
除非有句子需要急救
Maybe if we need to revive a sentence.
但你为什么会有这种药?
Well, why do you have synthetic smack anyway?
那是什么?
What is that?
该死
Oh, shit.
妈?
Mother?
嘿
Hey.
嘿 你在干什么?
Hey. What are you doing? Hey.
妈
Mother.
嘿
Hey.
还好吗?
Come on.
别这样
老实说 我也不清楚
Well, I'm not sure, to be honest with you.
要看医生怎么说
It's going to depend on what the doctors say.
有更多信息我再跟你说
Yeah, I'll touch base when I know more.
感谢你的体谅
Thanks so much for being understanding.
李奥 还有一件事
Hey, um, Leo, one more thing.
也许我们可以把这件事
I was wondering if maybe we could treat this
视为学术休假而不是请假
as a sabbatical as opposed to a leave of absence?
不管我妈怎么了 都需要花钱
Whatever happens with my mother, it's going to cost some money.
不 我了解
No, I understand.
这不是你的错
No, it's not your fault.
我会再想办法
I'll figure something out.
感谢你的帮忙
Yeah. Thanks for your help.
好 再见
Okay. Bye-bye.
可恶
你不用这么做
You don't have to do that.
不 我想这么做
Oh, no. I do.
现在是西红柿季 可不能浪费了
It's tomato season. You can't let them go to waste.
那可是暴殄天物
Ooh.  -A crime around here.
谢谢
Thank you.
这就是邻居应尽的义务 对吧?
That's what neighbors are for, right?
欢迎搬到这区
Welcome to the neighborhood.
我以为这间房屋是空屋
I thought the place was vacant.
它确实空了一阵子
Uh, it has been for a while.
我们昨晚才到
We just got here last night.
我以为这里闹鬼
Oh. Figured the place was haunted.
听说有个老人在这  开枪轰了自己的脑袋
They said some old man blew his brains out there a while back.
对
Yeah.
噢 我的天 我…
Oh, my God. I...
我真是个该死的白痴
I'm a fucking idiot.
请原谅我
Please forgive me.
没关系
Well...
我很遗憾
Oh, I'm very sorry to hear that.
她是做什么的?
What'd she do for a living?
她是医生
She was a doctor. Um...
我大部分的家人都是医生
Most of my family, doctors.
基本上 我是个局外人
Basically, I'm the outcast.
你是做什么的?
Um, what do you do for work?
我是律师
I'm a lawyer.
公设辩护人 在昆西
Public defense. Quincy.
很值得尊敬
Very honorable.
是啊 很不容易 但很有成就感
Yeah. It's very hard, but can be rewarding.
我可以问一个  很多人都会问的问题吗?
May I ask you something that I'm sure a lot of people ask you?
替罪犯辩护的感觉是什么?
How do I feel about defending guilty people?
对  -我很喜欢
Yeah. I love it.
为什么?   -我得替他们辩护 而他们都有罪
Why? I have to. And they're all guilty.
真的吗?   -对 但没有关系
Really?  -Yes. But that's okay.
在罪行背后 人们还是有他的价值
People are more than their worst deed.
我想我同意  -我想也是
I guess I agree with that. Mm. Sure you do.
你是作家  -我不懂
You're a writer. I don't follow.
作家都必须保持中立
Well, writers have to be non-judgmental.
你不能写出一些有趣的角色
You can't write interesting characters
却又同时批评他们所做的错误决定
and be critical of every bad decision they make. Right?
也许你才该当作家  我最近没什么当作家的感觉
Maybe you should be the writer. I don't feel like much of one lately.
你遇到写作瓶颈了?
You blocked?
只是…
It's just...
我觉得人们不想买我写的书
I don't think anybody wants to buy what I write.
才不呢
That's not true.
我本来不想透露
I didn't want to say anything,
但我其实有读过你的某本书
but, um, I actually read one of your books.
哪本?
Hm. Which?
《青蛙》
The Frogs.
原来就是你
Oh, so you were the one.
我很喜欢
I liked it.
你很有才华
You're talented.
有人要来吗?
You're expecting company?
对
Yeah.
你好  -嘿
Hello. Hey.
杰拉尼 这是莫克
Jelani, uh, this is Monk.
对街的房子是他和他家人的
He and his family own the house across the street.
很高兴见到你  -我也是
Nice to meet you. Yeah, it's a pleasure.
你要留下来吃晚餐吗?
Are you staying for dinner?
不了 我要去看我妈
Uh...No, I need to go check in on my mother.
好的  -谢谢你…
Cool. Thank you, uh...
招待我喝酒 晚安
For the wine, and... good night.
晚安 莫克
Good night, Monk.
你的飞机是几点?   -11点
What time's your flight? 11:00.
可以改时间吗?
You think, uh, maybe you could change it?
如果你能来一起跟妈看诊会很有帮助
Think it would be useful to have you at Mother's doctor's appointment today.
没办法 我得回家
I can't. I got to get home.
好 那你可以帮忙出点照护费吗?
Fine, but you think you can chip in
一旦我们找出病因后?
for her care once we find out what's what?
也许会很贵
It's probably going to be pretty expensive.
我手头有点紧
Things are tight right now, so...
你有想过解雇罗兰吗?
You thought about firing Lorraine?
罗兰算家人了  -该死 莫克
Lorraine is family. Well, shit, Monk.
我不知道该怎么说
I don't know what to tell you, all right?
所以你什么都帮不上忙?
So you can't do anything?
我回去后会跟会计师讨论 好吗?
I will check with my accountant when I get back, all right?
现在才早上八点
It's 8:00 in the morning.
我又没有要开飞机 莫克
I'm not flying the fucking plane, Monk.
你愿意进门去
Well, do you think you could be so kind
看看妈准备出门了没吗?
as to go inside and see if Mother is ready to head out?
好吧 嘿
All right. Hey.
妈  -别大吼 文明点
Mother!  -Don't yell, man. Be civilized.
你实在跟爸很像
You're just like our dad, man.
你只会数落我 莫克
So you do right by me, Monk.
我向天发誓
I swear to fucking God.
白痴
Clown.
想知道文明人是怎样吗?  妈
You want to see civilized? Mother!
早安
Morning.
嘿 早安
Hey. Morning.
听着
Listen...
关于昨晚…
about last night, uh---Oh.
没关系
It's okay.
你不用解释 我昨晚很开心
You don't have to explain. I had a good time.
不 我…
No, I...
杰拉尼是我前男友
Jelani, he's my ex.
即将成为前男友
Well, he's going to be.
我们正在分手中
We're in the middle of breaking up and...
这实在不容易
it's hard.
我懂
I get it.
我想再跟你相处
I'd like to see you again.
你接下来几天会在镇上吗?
Do you think that you'll be around town next couple of days?
可以喝一杯
You know, grab a drink?
好啊
Yeah, I'd like that.
好 我也是
Yeah, me too.
开车小心
Drive safe.
谢谢
Thanks.
金童
我总想从文学世界中获益更多
痛苦却真实
紧急、原始
艾里森先生?
Mr. Ellison?
我们准备好了
We're ready.
她的磁共振成像显示  她有初期神经退化现象
Her MRI shows early signs of neurodegeneration.
颞叶逐渐缩小
There's a slight decrease in the size of the temporal lobe
表示可能有阿兹海默症
which suggest Alzheimer's.
我很遗憾 艾里森先生
I'm very sorry, Mr. Ellison.
但之后她可能会需要
But at some point, she'll probably require
全天候的照顾
around-the-clock care
这是为了她的安全
for her own safety.
辛塔拉·戈登
《我的病理学》
《我有病》
斯塔格·R·利亚著
嘿 黑鬼小子  -嘿
Hey, young nigga.  -Hey!
嘿 等等
Hey, whoa, whoa.
别开枪 伙伴 别这样
Don't shoot me, partner. Come on now.
范哥 是你吗?
Van Go. That you?
对 是我 老兄
Yeah, me, nigga.
靠 你喝醉了吗 小混蛋?
Shit. What, you drunk, motherfucker?
你要去哪里?
Where you running to?
别管我 老兄
Just leave me alone, man.
你妈还好吗?
How your mama?
你说什么?   -我说 你妈还好吗?
What you say? I said, how your mama?
靠
Oh, shit.
他们没告诉你吗?
They ain't tell you, huh?
你在说什么?
What you talking about, punk?
嘿 你在说什么?
Hey, what you talking about?
你想想 范哥
Think about it, Van Go.
看我的脸
Look at my face.
看我黝黑的脸庞
Look at my midnight black complex...
不 不太对劲
No, that's not right.
你想怎么说?
What did you want to say?
你可以再说好一点吧?   对吧 你想怎样?
You can say it better than that, right? Come on. What do you want?
看我黝黑的…
你想想 范哥
Think about it, Van Go.
看我的脸
Look at my face.
看我黝黑的皮肤
Look at my coal black skin.
然后看看你自己的
And then look at your own.
看我乌黑的眼睛
Look at my black eyes.
再看看你自己的
Now look at your own.
看我厚实的黑唇
Look at my big black lips.
再看看你自己的
Now look at your own.
无论你喜不喜欢 我就是你老子
I's your daddy whether you like it or not.
闭嘴 别说了 你这骗子
Shut up, okay? Shut up, man! You lying!
不 这是实话 小子
No, no, that's the truth, nigga.
你都去哪里了?
So, where you been, huh?
你去哪里了?
Where you been?
我一直都在我该在的地方
I've been where I always be.
努力生存
Surviving.
你连屎尿都不如
You ain't worth a piss.
你妈屎尿都不如 所以我才来
Your mama ain't worth a piss. So here I am.
我现在要说什么?
What do I say now?
现在应该要说点
I think now will come some sort of, you know,
愚蠢且令人难过的故事
dumb, melodramatic sob story
你会强调你破碎的心灵
where you, uh, highlight your broken interiority.
类似 我也不知道
Something... something like, um, I don't know...
我恨透这个男人
I hates this man.
我恨透我妈
I hates my mama.
我也恨透我自己
And I hates myself.
我在他的面容中看到我自己
I've seen my face in his.
我看到那头女孩们都害怕的野兽
I see the ape that all them stupid girls were afraid of, yeah.
我可以看到我垂在身边的一双长手
I can see my long arms hanging down.
也可以看到我不在乎明日的双眼
And I see eyes that don't care what happens tomorrow.
我看到我自己
I see myself
就像这样站着晃着
rocking back on my heels, just like this, baby.
正在等待
Just waiting.
不断等待 等待某事
And waiting, and waiting, and waiting, and waiting for something
等待连我都不知道是什么的事
that I'm not even going to recognize when it comes!
死亡是唯一的解药
Death is my only cure.
我以前就听过这种说法
I heard that before.
我一直都有听说 现在也是如此
I've been hearing it, and I'm hearing it now.
我看到
I see...
我看到我妈在哭泣
I see my mama crying.
我看到她在我梦中尖叫
I see her screaming in my dreams.
我看到我的孩子
I see my babies.
我看到我的…
I see my...
我看到我爸
I see my daddy.
我看到我自己
I see myself.
搞屁啊
What the fuck?
你为何这样?
What the fuck you do that for?
因为你不废
Because you ain't shit, nigga.
你创造了我
And you made me.
因为你不废 我也不废
So because you ain't shit, I ain't shit.
你不废 我也不废
Because you ain't shit, I ain't shit.
我得走了
I gots to bounce.
再会啦 混蛋
Peace, motherfucker.
再见
Peace.
刚才那是什么鬼?
What the fuck was that for?
你正在WHN收看《黑人故事月》
You're watching Black Stories Month on WHN.
颂扬非裔美国人的多元经验
Celebrating the diversity of the African-American experience.
请继续收看更多引人入胜的电影  心碎和戏剧
Join us for more riveting cinema, heartbreak, and drama.
喂?
Hello?
我在夜晚中站在户外
"I be standing outside in the night,
一台警用直升机飞过
a police chopper go by
用探照灯打在后院
and shine some lights in some backyards
我想："把光打在我身上吧 混蛋
and I think, 'Shine that light on me, motherfucker,
把该死的光打在我身上
shine me some fucking light
我才能看见我到底身在何方"
so I can see where the fuck I be at.'"
你是认真的吗?
Are you serious?
你有发现我没放我的名字吗?
You notice I didn't put my name on it.
对 你放斯塔格·R·利亚
Yes, Stagg R. Leigh,
我有发现 很棒
I did notice that. Well done.
但我还是没把它送出去
But I still can't send this out.
你说你想要黑人文学  这个不够黑吗?
You said you wanted Black stuff. What's Blacker than that?
里头有游手好闲的爸爸  饶舌歌手、毒品
It's got deadbeat dads, rappers, crack,
他最后还被警察杀了
and he gets killed by a cop in the end.
这样很黑对吧?
I mean, that's... that's... that's Black, right?
我知道你在干什么  -很好 因为这一点都不隐讳
I see what you're doing. Good, because it's not subtle.
这本书跟其他出版社
I mean, how's that book so different
出的垃圾书们有什么差别?
than some of the other garbage they put out?
那不是重点  -这就是我的重点
That's not the point. Well, it's my point.
你看看他们出版的东西
Look at what they publish.
看看他们要我们写的东西
Look at what they expect us to write.
我感到厌恶
I'm sick of it.
这是我表达厌恶的方式
And that's an expression of how sick I am.
莫克 我想要卖书
Monk, I'm trying to sell books,
而非参加某种圣战行动
not be a part of some crusade.
有谁会想出这种书?
Who do you expect to publish this?
没人
No one.
我只希望他们碰了一鼻子灰
I just want to rub their noses in the horseshit they solicit.
好 那你希望我怎么做?
Okay. What do you want me to do?
我要你把稿子送出去
I want you to send it out.
我可以说这是表演艺术吗?
Can I say it's performance art?
不 直接送出
No. Send it straight.
若他们开不起玩笑 就去死吧
If they can't take the joke, then fuck them.
好 但我只想寄给几家出版社就好
All right, but I'm only sending it to a couple of places.
这东西吓到我了
This thing scares me.
吓到你? 为什么?
Scares you? Why?
因为白人希望能看到真相  事实却不然
Because white people think they want the truth, but they don't.
他们只想感到被饶恕
They just want to feel absolved.
幸好那不是我的问题
Well, fortunately, that's not my problem.
好  -再见
Okay.  -Bye.
冰淇淋
我很惊讶你来找我  我以为你只是表示友善而已
I'm surprised you reached out. I thought you were just being nice.
我从不只是表示友善
Oh, I'm never just being nice.
我这年纪已经不干这种事了
I'm too old for that.
我很喜欢你 事实上
You know, I like you so much, in fact,
我又去买了你的另一本书
that I went out and got another one of your books.
真的吗? 哪本?
Really? Which one?
《海斯难题》
The Haas Conundrum.
你觉得如何?
What'd you think?
我很喜欢
I liked it.
苏珊的对白很棒
Susan has really great dialogue.
我也喜欢里面的阿姨
And I love the aunt.
你很会描写女性
Wow. I mean, you write women well.
真的吗?
Oh, you think so?
对啊 她们不再是温室花朵  -谢谢
Yeah. They're not hothouse flowers. Thank you.
谢谢你这么说
I appreciate that.  -Mm.
但我觉得不需要有那么多批注
I could've done with less footnotes though.
我得走了
I, uh... I got to run.
你妈还好吗?
Well, how's your mom?
时好时坏
In and out.
我可能离开太久了
I'm afraid to be away for too long.
好  -但是…
Yeah.  -But, uh...
我会再打给你
I'll, uh... I'll call you.
等等
Hold on a minute.
《海斯难题》塞洛尼斯·艾里森
帮我的书签名
Sign my book.
你叫什么名字?
What's your name again?
莫克先生?
Mr. Monk?
怎么没有灯?
What's going on with the lights?
莉莎小姐以前会负责付电费
Miss Lisa used to pay the bill.
你付了吗?
Did you?
多少钱?
How much?
我可以负责电费
Well, I can handle the electrical bills,
但照护机构实在太贵了
but these care facilities are expensive.
最近又最好的一家  每个月要交5600
The best one nearby is $5,600 a month,
而且还是多人房
and that's for a shared room.
单人房的话是6900
It goes up to $6,900 a month for a private room.
你为何一定要找最好的?   她又不是世上最好的母亲
Well, why you looking at the best one? She wasn't the best mother.
听着 我不是来重提儿时恩怨的
Look, I'm not here to re-litigate our childhoods.
当然不是 因为你的童年很棒
Of course not, because yours was great.
该死 你到底要不要帮忙?
Goddamn it! Are you going to help me or not?
有医疗福利可以帮忙吗?
Won't Medicaid cover it or something?
那不是这么用的 你不知道吗?
That's not how it works. You don't know this?
你好
Oh. Hello.
那是谁? 你在干什么?
Who's that? What are you doing?
我要去上我爱人
I've taken a lover.
你要去上你爱人?
You've taken a lover?
有什么问题吗? 恐同人士?
You got a problem with that, homophobe?
听着 你要去上你爱人  不会冒犯我 克里夫
Listen, I'm not offended that you've taken a lover, Cliff.
我被冒犯的地方 克里夫  是你说："你要去上你爱人"
I'm offended, Cliff, that you call it taking a lover.
去吃屎吧 黑鬼
Mm, you can eat shit, nigga.
我现在要去上我爱人了
I'll take my lover right now.
嘿 你要去哪?
Hey, where you going?
你来了
There you are.
路上堵车 怎么了?
Traffic was insane. What's up?
坐吧
Sit down.
坐下
Have a seat.
我卖掉你的书了
We sold your book.
老天
Holy shit!
我以为这本书没救了  -波斯人可不这么认为
I thought it was DOA.  -Not The Persians.
不会吧
No.
太狂了
Get out!
是汤普森·瓦特出版社的葆拉·贝特曼
Paula Betaman from Thompson-Watt.
她每次都拒绝
She always passes.
这次可没有  他们想以75万美金抢先购入
Not this time. They want to preempt for $750,000.
从没有人给我这样的价格
No one's ever offered that much to me.
现在你得到了  -不 阿瑟
This is you.  -No, it's not, Arthur.
书是你写的  -我是写来闹笑话的
You wrote it.  -As a joke.
那这就是你说过最好赚的笑话了
Well, now it's the most lucrative joke you've ever told.
我不要卖  -为什么?
And I'm not selling.  -Why not?
因为那是垃圾 阿瑟
Because it's trash, Arthur.
你之前甚至不想把它寄出去
You didn't even want to send it out the other day.
但看看是谁瞬间不怕了
Oh, but look who's suddenly overcome his fears.
我知道 我为了销售破戒
I know, I broke the first rule of sales.
绝对不要小看人们愚蠢的程度
Never underestimate how stupid everyone is.
我不要再让这件事更加愚蠢了
Well, I'm not participating in making them any stupider.
你目前还没
Well, you haven't thus far,
这的确值得令人敬佩 但是…
which is admirable, but...
你也还没赚到钱
you also haven't made any money.
难道你妈不需要这笔钱吗?
Doesn't your mom need help these days?
你看
Check this out.
我不管我被灌多醉 我不要卖
I don't care how drunk we get, I'm not selling it.
我没有要这么做
That's not what I'm doing.
约翰走路红牌威士忌 24美金
Johnnie Walker Red, 24 bucks.
约翰走路黑牌威士忌 50美金
Johnnie Walker Black, 50 bucks.
约翰走路蓝牌威士忌 160美金
Johnnie Walker Blue...$160.
你懂我的比喻了吗?
You see the metaphor?
不懂
No.
这些都是同公司制造的酒
These are all made by the same company.
红牌很难喝 黑牌没那么难喝  蓝牌很好喝
The Red is shit, the Black is less shit, the Blue is good.
但很少人买蓝牌 因为很贵
But fewer people buy the blue because it's expensive.
而大家一天终了之时只想喝醉
And at the end of the day, most people just want to get drunk.
你的职涯中 你的书都是蓝牌
For most of your career, your books have been Blue.
都很棒 很复杂
They're good, complex.
但它们并不受欢迎  因为人们只想看好读的书
But they're not popular because most people want something easy.
你生平第一次写出红牌书
Now, for the first time ever, you've written a Red book.
简单又低俗
It's simple, prurient.
不是好的文学作品  却满足人们的需要
It's not great literature, but... satisfies an urge.
这是很宝贵的
And that's valuable.
我想要描述的是  只因为你写了红牌书
What I'm trying to illustrate is that, just because you do Red
不表示你写不出蓝牌
doesn't mean you can't also do Blue.
你什么书都能写
You can do it all.
就像约翰走路一样
Like Johnnie Walker.
事实上 你比约翰走路还强 因为…
In fact, you got Johnnie Walker beat, because...
你还不用放上你真正的名字
you don't even have to put your real name on it.
老天
Jesus.
要开喝了吗?
Do we drink now?
喂?   -喂 葆拉
Hello? Hello, Paula.
阿瑟 很高兴接到你的电话
Arthur! So wonderful to hear from you.
希望你有跟那位当红炸子鸡在一起
Um, I hope that you are with the man of the hour.
没错 他就坐在我旁边
I am, indeed. He's right here next to me.
利亚先生?
Mr. Leigh?
我就是
Uh, yeah, this is he.
真的吗?
Oh, really?
对 怎么了吗?
Yeah, goddamn it.
好耶  -去你的
Right. Right. Okay.  -Motherfucker.
好的
我本来有点疑惑 但是…
Yeah, I was a little confused at first, but...
我们都很期待  讨论汤普森·瓦特的开价
We're both very excited to discuss Thompson-Watt's offer.
好的 首先我得说
Yes, well, first of all, let me just say
汤普森·瓦特的全体同仁  都很爱《我有病》
that all of us here at Thompson-Watt are thrilled with My Pafology.
这真是长久以来最完美的书了
It is about as perfect a book as I have seen in a long, long while.
很直接很真实
Just... just raw and real.
利亚先生 这是改编自  你的真实故事吗?
And, Mr. Leigh, is this based on your actual life?
对啊 难道你以为这个故事
Yeah, you think some bitch-ass college boy
是某个大学屁孩想出来的吗?
can come up with that shit?
不 我没有
No, no. No, I don't.
书中那股…
No. You know, that kind of
原始能量是学不来的 对吧?
visceral energy cannot be taught, right?
斯塔格…我可以这么称呼你吗?
Stagg... May I call you--
斯塔格是笔名吗?
Now, is Stagg a pseudonym?
是的
Yes, uh, it is.
利亚先生不能用本名 因为他是…
Mr. Leigh can't use his real name because he's a...
他是通缉犯
Well, he's a wanted fugitive.
我的天 哇
Oh, my God. Wow.
所以他才不能进行视频通话
That's why this couldn't be a video conference.
你疯了吗? 万一他们去查证怎么办?
Are you crazy? What if they fact check this?
查证? 他们连付编辑的费用都快没了
I checked. There's barely money to pay editors anymore.
就跟着演出吧
Just go with it.
对 我才刚坐牢12年  我不要再回去了
Yeah, I did a 12-year bid, but no going back.
你懂我的意思吗?
Know what I mean?
我懂 这样吧
Yeah. Yeah, you know, um...
我读了很多关于废除监狱运动的书
I've been reading a lot about the prison abolition movement...
老天  -我已…
Oh, God!  -I've...
很抱歉催促你 葆拉  但我们可以谈正事吗?
Sorry to rush, Paula, but can we talk business?
利亚先生很重视他狱外的时间
Mr. Leigh values his time outside of a cell.
当然 我相信你们都很忙
Of course. I'm sure you're both very, very busy
那么我就直接讲重点吧
so I will get right to it.
你会发现稿费非比寻常地高
Um, you'll notice that our offer is...unusually large
那是因为我们相信  利亚先生写出了畅销书
and that is because we believe Mr. Leigh has written a bestseller.
我们认为那会是今夏必读的畅销书
We think it is going to be the read of the summer.
我相信汉普顿的白人们
Yeah, I'm sure white people on the Hamptons
会很喜欢这本书
will delight in it.
没错 一定会 我们…
Yes, we will. They--We--
这本书一定会热卖
It's going to be huge. Huge.
我爱死了
I love it.
是塞洛尼斯·艾里森吗?
Is that little Thelonious Ellison?
老天 米纳
My God! Maynard!
大家都还是称呼你为莫克吗?
Everyone still call you Monk?
除了你之外都是这样
Well, everyone but you.
那是个很美的名字
Well, it's a beautiful name.
不完整称呼实在太罪过了
It seems simple not to use it whole.
很高兴有人喜欢
Well, I'm glad someone appreciates it.
我听说你妹的事了 请节哀
I heard about your sister. My condolences.
谢谢
Thank you.
我好像很久没看到你了
I don't think I've seen you since
自从你父亲过世后
before your father passed?
是啊 好一阵子了  我现在住在洛杉矶
Yeah, it's been a while. I live in LA now.
好莱坞
Oh! Hollywood.
你是《重返犯罪现场》的编剧吗?
Hey, do you write for that NCIS?
我只有写书
Just books.
你应该去当《重返犯罪现场》的编剧  那部戏很红
Well, you should try to write for NCIS. It's popular.
也许吧 再看看
Well, maybe I will.
你最近过得如何?
Hey, so, how you been?
还不错 你呢?   -这个嘛
Oh, I'm good. And you? Yeah...
莫克先生 你晚餐想吃什么?
Mr. Monk. What would you like for dinner?
米纳  -嗨 罗兰
Maynard! Hi, Lorraine.
好久不见了
It's been a dog's age.
我想也是
Well, I guess it has.
你看起来还不错
You look well.
你也是
You too.
我得回去了
Well, I best be getting back.
很高兴见到你 塞洛尼斯  -我也很高兴
It's good to see you, Thelonious. You too.
罗兰
Lorraine.
没什么好笑的
Ain't nothing to smile at.
她来了
Oh! There she is.
乖一点
Behave yourself.
嘿  -嗨
Hey. Hi.
这个是送你的  -谢谢
Got this for you.  -Oh, thank you.
罗兰 这是卡罗琳
Lorraine, this is Coraline.  -Oh.
嘿  -欢迎
Hey.  -Welcome.
你好  -你好
Yeah, hello.  -Hello.
妈 这时机真好 她是卡罗琳
Mother, perfect timing. This is Coraline.
你好 亲爱的 我是爱格妮斯
Hello, dear, I'm Agnes.
很高兴见到你 我买了这些
Such a pleasure to meet you. I brought you these.
我最爱大丽花了
Dahlias are my favorite.
花瓣中藏了一整个世界
There's a whole world inside them.
罗兰?   -好的
Lorraine?  -Yes.
妈 你坐这里
Mother, you sit here.
好的
All right.
卡罗琳 你坐我妈对面好吗?
And, Coraline, why don't you sit across from Mother?
好的
Oh, sure, sure.
好
Okay.
我很高兴你不是白人
I'm happy you're not white.
我也是
Me too.
对啊 满好笑的
Yeah, it was pretty funny.
我觉得你…
Well, I think you...
你让我想到我妹
I think you remind her of my sister.
你觉得我们很像吗?
Well, do you think we look alike?
不像 但是…
No, but...
你们都很有自信 也很幽默
you're both self-assured...and funny...
你们也都…
and you're both...
吻技很好
fantastic kissers.
艾里森太太?
Mrs. Ellison?
莫克先生
Mr. Monk!
我只是…  -怎么了?
I just... I just...  -What's wrong?
我只是出来一下子  -怎么了?
I just stepped outside for a moment. What's wrong?
跟米纳喝杯咖啡 就在前面而已
Having a cup of coffee with Maynard, I was right in front.
妈呢?   -我不知道
Where's Mother? I don't know!
什么?   -后门是开的
What?  The backdoor was open.
她不见了  -什么?
She gone.  -What?
我们分开去找她 给你
We should split up. Here.
我车上还有更多
I got more in the car.
妈
Mother!
Mother.
妈
Mother!
妈！嘿！
Mother! Hey!
妈
Mother! Mother!
嘿 停下来
Hey! Hey, stop!
嘿 你要去哪里?
Hey! Where are you going?
莉莎在外头跟表亲起争执
Lisa's out there roughhousing with the cousins.
有人会受伤
Somebody's going to get hurt.
停下来 妈 我会告诉她 好吗?
Stop. Um... I will go tell her. Okay?
好 但是…  -我带你回家
Yeah, but then---I'll take you back to the house
然后我会去告诉她
and then I will go tell her.
但他们在外面  -我知道
But they're out there. I know, I know.
你确定吗?   -我会告诉她
Okay, you sure?  -I will tell her.
好  -走吧
Okay.  -Now, come on.
外头太冷了  -你应该…
It's too cold out here. You should...
莉莎不太会游泳  -我知道
Okay. Lisa doesn't swim very well. I know. I know.
好 快到了
Okay. Almost there.
没事了
All right.
很好  -走吧
Oh, good. Good.
好的  -很好
Here we go.All right.
好的 莫克
Okay, Monkie.
好
All right.
这是我们的图书馆
And this is our library.
里面有各种经典作品
It's full of all the classics.
我们也会买新的书
And we try to get some new releases too.
你喜欢阅读吗 艾里森太太?
Do you like to read, Mrs. Ellison?
不喜欢
No.
才怪 她很爱读书
That's not true. She loves to read.
是她教我爱上阅读的
She taught me to love reading.
也许我们可以买一些你儿子的书
Perhaps we can get some of your son's books in here.
你可以带领读书会
And you can lead a book club.
抱歉
Sorry.
没关系 这对新入住居民并不容易
It's fine. It's hard for a lot of the residents at first.
但她会习惯的  -好
But she'll settle in. Right.
很感谢你的帮忙
I appreciate all your help,
但你觉得她多快能住进来?
but how soon do you think we can get her in?
大概一个月
Uh, in about a month.
你如果愿意的话  今天可以开始准备文件
You can start the paperwork today if you'd like.
太好了 没问题
Great. I'd like that.
我去看你妈 好吗?
I'll go check on your mom, okay?
谢谢
Thank you.
喂?   -嘿 塞洛尼斯
Hello?  - [Carl] Hey, Thelonious.
你好吗? 我叫卡尔·布朗特
How you doing? My name is Carl Brunt.
我是新英格兰图书协会的首席执行官
I am the director of the New England Book Association.
嗨 卡尔 我知道你是谁
Hi, Carl. I know who you are.
很好 那么也许你也会知道
Oh, good. Then perhaps you'll also know
我们组织每年都会举行
that each year my organization bestows
自以为是的"文学奖"
the somewhat pretentiously named Literary Award.
每位作家都知道文学奖 卡尔
Every writer knows the Literary Award, Carl.
特别是我们这些还没得奖的人
Especially those of us who haven't won it.
对啦
Yeah. Yeah.
这也是我打来的原因
Well, that's sort of related to why I'm calling.
像其他许多美国组织  我们最近被批评
Like many American institutions, mine was recently rattled by the notion
因缺乏多元性
that our lack of diversity
导致奖项有其盲点
had led to a blind spot in our work.
所以我们正试图修正这点
So, you know, we're kind of trying to remedy that.
因此 我们想知道你是否愿意
And to that end, I was wondering how you might feel
担任今年奖项的评审?
about being a judge in this year's award ceremony?
首先 卡尔 我很荣幸
Um, let me say first, Carl, that I'm honored you choose me
你冒着被批评种族歧视的风险
out of all the Black writers you could go to out of fear
在所有黑人作家中选了我
of being called racist.
不客气
Yeah, you're very welcome.
但我觉得这个工作很辛苦
But I think this sounds like a lot of work.
我不否认
Yeah, I can't deny that.
你要读好几十本书
I mean, you're going to have to read dozens of books.
我们可以提供你不错的津贴
We could offer you a modest stipend.
即便如此 我仍无法决定
Even so, I'm not sure.
好 当人们这样持观望态度时
Okay. One of the crass perk I reference
我会用一种的粗俗的方式去说服
when people are kind of on the fence like this
就是这能让你有机会
is that this will allow you the opportunity
真正去评审这些作品
to literally judge these other writers for once,
而非形而上的批评
rather than just figuratively.
好 我参加  -太棒了 很好
All right, I'm in. Well, fantastic. Okay.
很好 所以你会成为五位评审之一
Great. So you're going to be one of five judges.
我们目前唯一确认的  只有辛塔拉·戈登
Uh, the only one we have confirmed so far is Sintara Golden.
你熟悉辛塔拉·戈登的著作吗?
Are you familiar with Sintara Golden's work?
不太熟悉
Vaguely.
她很棒 你会喜欢她的 老兄
Oh, she's great. You're going to love her, man.
你的午餐带来了 莫克先生
I brought you lunch, Mr. Monk.
哇
Oh, wow.
你怎么会对我这么好?
To what do I owe the pleasure?
我有个请求
Well, I have a favor to ask.
我想问我这个下午是否能请假
I was wondering if I might be able to take the afternoon off.
米纳刚从海滩来
Maynard just came in from the beach.
我们想去参观博物馆
And we thought it might be nice to visit a museum.
好啊 当然可以
Yes, of course.
我今天没事 我可以照顾妈
I'm free today, so I can look after Mother.
罗兰
Lorraine.
你真的很喜欢他 对吧?
You really like him, huh?
他是个不错的人
He's a fine man.
喂
Yeah.
第七页 有12个
Page seven. It's got like 12.
贵宾来了
The guests of honor.
你好 艾里森太太
Hello, Mrs. Ellison.
你就像以往一样美丽
Looking beautiful as ever.
你好 阿瑟
Hello, Arthur.
莲恩 请带艾里森太太到茶水间
Layne, would you take Mrs. Ellison to the kitchen,
泡茶给她喝
and set her up with some tea?
往这边走 女士  -妈 我马上过去
Right this way, ma'am. Mother, I won't be long.
慢慢来
Take your time.
谢谢
Thank you.  -Mm-hm.
不要用茶包的 用好的茶叶  给客人喝的那种
Not the pods. The good tea, for guests.
这是什么? 我要你穿街头一点
What is this? I told you to dress street.
我有啊  -该死的芝麻街风
I did.  -Fucking Sesame Street.
这家伙的名字是什么?
What's this guy's name?
威利?   -瓦利 瓦利瓦尔斯皮诺
Willy?  -Wiley. Wiley Valdespino.
他的专长是奥斯卡爱的议题电影
He specializes in Oscar-baity "issue" movies.
他去年拍了《中央走廊》
He did the Middle Passage one last year.
我没看过那部
Somehow I didn't see that.
当然没有 你大脑又没动手术
Of course, not. You're not lobotomized.
但如果他改编你的书
But if he adapts your book,
你将会赚一大笔钱
you stand to make a lot of money.
为什么不能打电话就好?
Why can't we just do a phone call?
他说若他要付这么大一笔钱
Well, he said if he's going to cut a check this large,
他需要与你亲自见面
then he needs to meet in person.
好吧
All right.
那我该怎么做?
What do I need to do?
让他喜欢你
Just make him like you.
我跟他聊天时
When I talked to him,
他听到你是逃犯时觉得很兴奋
he seemed thrilled that you're a fugitive.
你就照这样演
Just, you know, play that up.
万一他认出我怎么办?
But what if he recognizes me?
你?   -对啊 真正的我
You?  -Yeah, the real me.
莫克 你又不有名
Monk, you're not that famous.
好莱坞没人会读书
And nobody in Hollywood reads.
他们只会叫助理读 然后整理给他们
They got their assistants to read things, and then summarize them.
那整座城市都非常仰赖书本简介
The whole town runs on book reports.
你确定你能照顾我妈吗?
You sure you can look after my mother?
我不会让她离开我的视线
She won't leave my sight.
反正你也只会在对街
You'll just be across the street, anyway.
对街  -你该走了 不然会迟到
Across the street. You should go. You'll be late.
他在等你
He's waiting for you.
这个嘛…
Well...
若他希望我是典型逃犯
if he, uh, wants the stereotype,
也许我最好迟到一下
maybe it's better I'm late.
你是斯塔格吗?
Stagg, I presume?
就是我  -嘿 我是瓦利
That's me. Hey, I'm Wiley.
很高兴见到你 老兄
Nice to meet you, brother.
很抱歉这是个烛光餐厅
Sorry about the bougie restaurant.
是我助理挑的
My assistant picked it.
若你很不安的话 我们可以换一间
We can go somewhere else if you're uncomfortable.
没关系  -好
This is fine.  -Okay.
你要喝什么?
What are you drinking?
我要喝白诗南酒
I'll have a Chenin Blanc.
好  -最不甜的那种
All right. Of your driest.
有什么好笑?
Well, what's funny?
这不太像是你这种人会点的饮料
Ah, it's just a strange order for a guy like you.
为什么?
Why is that?
没什么罪犯会喝白酒
Well, you don't see many convicts drinking white wine.
你认识很多罪犯吗?
You know many convicts?
说出来会让你吃惊
You'd be surprised.
我自己坐过一个月的牢
I spent a month in the joint myself.
因为违反某种商业条款
It was some interstate commerce shit.
时间很短暂 但告诉你
It was a short stay, but I'll tell you what,
那个经验成就了现在的我
that experience grounded me.
我在里面遇到的人让我发掘
The people I met in there allowed me to see
世上有一群无名小卒
a whole world of underrepresented stories
他们的故事需要被大众所知
from underrepresented storytellers.
我可以问你坐牢的原因吗?
Can I ask what you were in for?
我不想谈这件事
I don't like to talk about that.
你懂吗?
You feel me?
是谋杀吗?
Was it murder?
是你说的 不是我
You said that, not me.
我得说 在你出现之前
You know, I got to tell you, before you showed up,
我有点担心你是骗子
I was a little worried you might be a phony.
好莱坞有一堆骗子
A lot of fakes in Hollywood.
我不是从好莱坞来的
Well, I'm not from Hollywood.
是啊 没错 很明显
Yeah, yeah, no. That's obvious. That's obvious.
显然 你跟一般的电影编剧
Clearly, you're cut from a different cloth
不太一样
than your average...screenwriter.
我问你
Let me ask you...
我知道他们有把我的作品寄给你
I know they sent you some of my stuff.
你有看过我的电影吗?
Did you have a chance to see any of my movies?
抱歉 你说什么?
Sorry, what did you say?
你有看过我的电影吗?
Have you seen any of my movies?
没有
Uh, no.
好 我想这么做
Okay. Well, look, what I like to do
我想结合电影类型  与显实世界中的苦难
is I like to pair genre with real-world pathos.
这样能更升华电影
It kind of elevates things.
你也许会对我们正要拍的电影有兴趣
You might be interested in this one we're about to shoot actually.
那是有关一对白人夫妻
It's about this white couple.
他们在路易斯安那州的老农庄结婚
They get married on an old plantation in Louisiana.
结果所有黑奴的魂魄都回来  谋杀所有人
Then all the slave ghosts come back, and they murder everyone.
老天  -我知道
Dear God.  -I know. I know.
很棒 对吧?
It's great, right?
电影叫做《农庄大毁灭》
It's called Plantation Annihilation.
瑞安·雷诺兹在电影开场
Ryan Reynolds is going to get decapitated
就会被一把黑人梳砍头
with an afro pick in the opening scene.
他是我朋友
He's a friend.
我得走了
Got to go.
妈
Mother. Mother. Mother. Mother!
某位三楼高层动脉瘤破裂
Some ad exec on the third floor had an aneurysm.
真惨  -我知道
Awful.  -I know.
想象为了厕所卫生纸广告
Imagine exploding your brain
而把脑子血管想炸
trying to think of a toilet paper commercial.
我想瓦利应该没兴趣
I assume Wiley isn't interested.
我像疯子一样冲过来
I sprinted out of there like a complete maniac.
其实他开价四百万美金以买版权
Actually, he's offering $4 million for the rights.
什么?   -没错
What?  -Yeah, man.
他说你是"绝佳人选"
He called you the real deal.
他说你一听到警车笛声就跑走了
Said you took off the moment you heard police sirens.
我表现越蠢就越有钱
The dumber I behave, the richer I get.
你终于知道  我父母为何要从波多黎各搬来
Now you know why my parents moved here from Puerto Rico.
他们不会逼我们
I mean, we can't be expected to read
完整读完每本小说 对吧?
every novel all the way through, right?
许多人在这些书上注入很多心血
No, people have worked hard on these books.
我们得尊重这点
And we have to respect that.
努力跟尊重没有直接关系
Well, hard work doesn't demand respect.
纳粹也很认真
I mean, you know, people worked hard on the Third Reich .
对啦 但我觉得
Yeah, well, I feel that
我们应该要好好读完 才对得起他们
we owe it to them to read every page.
真是胡说八道
That is such horseshit.
大部分的文学作品
I mean, most of it's going to be
都是像克瑙斯加德那样的伪自传
that Knausgard auto-fiction crap, anyhow.
让我告诉你
I tell you something right now,
我才不要读600页的书
I'm not reading 600 pages about some pretentious jackwagon
去看某个蠢蛋发现自慰
discovering masturbation.
抱歉
Sorry.
听着 我们都已经很有经验
Okay, look, I think we're all experienced enough
能够在100页内了解一本书的质量
to assess the general quality of something within 100 pages.
若你想读超过100页 请自便
If you want to read beyond that, that's your prerogative.
你的想法呢 莫克?
Well, how do you feel, Monk?
我同意辛塔拉 我认为读100页够了
Um, I agree with Sintara, actually. I think 100 pages is sufficient.
反正这一切都没什么用
You know, this is all a crock, anyway.
比较文学作品以颁奖
I mean, pitting art against other art for awards,
假装公正客观
like, it's not subjective.
太荒谬了
It's absurd.
若你这么觉得 你为何还要当评审?
Then why did you agree to be a judge if you feel that way?
因为他们不选我  也会选别的布鲁克林蠢蛋
Well, because it's either me or some other Brooklyn hack
他们的世界不会超过哈德逊河 艾琳
who doesn't think there's a world beyond the Hudson River, Ailene.
在布鲁克林的话是东河 丹尼尔
It's the East River if you're in Brooklyn, Daniel.
但这是一个机会 能让被低估的书
But I think this is an opportunity to highlight books
得到亮相的机会
that may otherwise be undervalued.
书的销量不断跳水
Book sales are plummeting right now.
也许这个奖项能让某人
So, perhaps this award can give someone
在业界闯出一番名号
a real chance at a career in this industry.
赞成
Hear, hear.
你想把这张画挂哪里呢 妈?
Where do you want this, Mother?
放在这里有自然光照很不错
Thought it might look nice here with this natural light.
我不在乎
I don't care.
反正我也不喜欢那张画
I never liked that painting, anyway.
好吧
Okay.
我们下周会从家里带更多画来
Uh, well, I'll bring some more art from home next week.
你告诉我你喜欢哪几幅 我就带过来
And you just tell me the pieces you like, and I'll bring them.
午餐准备好了 艾里森太太
We've got your lunch ready for you, Mrs. Ellison.
很棒吧 这是什么?
Oh, it looks great. What is it?
是烤火鸡和谷物干酪面包
It's roasted turkey and Havarti on 12-grain.
好像很好吃
Sounds delicious.
艾里森太太喜欢白面包
Mrs. Ellison prefers white bread.
她也不喜欢酥脆
And she doesn't like the crust.
这地方这么贵
As much as this place costs,
也该把三明治做好吧
y'all should get the sandwiches right.
我们之后一定会改进 好吗?
I'll make sure that we take care of that from now on, okay?
请享用你的午餐 艾里森太太
And enjoy your lunch, Mrs. Ellison.
我要结婚了
I'm getting married.
不会吧  -什么?
Shut up.  -What?
我刚刚什么都没说  我觉得很伤心 但是…
I didn't say nothing earlier. I was just so sad. But
米纳昨天向我求婚
Maynard asked me yesterday.
罗兰 太棒了
Lorraine, that's amazing.
我们去庆祝吧
I mean, let's celebrate.  -Mm-mm!
那样就兴奋过头了
Just too much excitement.
我不想成为众人焦点
I don't like being the center of attention.
但你值得 罗兰
Well, you deserve it, Lorraine.
米纳是个幸运的男人
And Maynard is a lucky man.
你会愿意
Do you think you'd be willing
牵我走红毯吗 莫克先生?
to walk me down the aisle, Mr. Monk?
这是我的荣幸
I'd be honored.
哇
Wow. Wow.
我们很兴奋能帮你出版《我有病》
We are wildly excited to help you get My Pafology out.
营销部门已有各种很棒的点子
The marketing team has all kinds
来帮你销售这本书
of great ideas to help you sell it.
太棒了 我们洗耳恭听
Great. We're excited to hear.
约翰博斯科是部门主管
John Bosco is the head of the department.
我请他来告诉你
I will let him tell you more.
嗨 斯塔格
Hi, Stagg.
你好  -很高兴终于能见到你 老兄
Hello. Nice to finally meet you, my man.
听着 我很爱这本书
Listen, I love the book.
我们一定会卖出很多册
And we are going to sell many, many copies.
改编成电影一事  已经为本书创造许多声量
There's already so much buzz because of the movie deal.
我们希望能持续保持这股热度
And we just want to keep that momentum going.
我昨天跟瓦利谈过
I spoke to Wiley yesterday.
他说迈克尔·B·乔丹  对这个作品很有兴趣
He says Michael B. Jordan is circling.
我们听说了 他会是个完美演员
We heard. We think he would be absolutely perfect.
这部电影很有得奖希望
You know, this book, it's awards-bait with a capital B.
若迈克尔愿意拍
And we're thinking that if Michael does sign on,
我们会把他放在封面
we want to put him on the cover
利用书腰
in one of those, um, scarves,
缠在他的头部
I guess you would call them, tied round his head.
头巾吗?
A durag?
没错 头巾和背心
Durag. That's it. Durag and a tank top
要展现出肌肉
with the muscles showing.
实在是太性感了
Ooh, somebody call the fire department. Yummy.
抱歉 让你想到你爸
Shit. Sorry. Your dad. Sorry.
听着 出版日期的部分
So listen, for a release date,
我们希望能加速流程
we're thinking of rushing it, so that we can get it out in time
才能赶上六月节  -对
for Juneteenth.  -Yeah.
六月节?
Juneteenth?
我们要利用节日大力促销
We're thinking of making a big holiday push.
黑人们会欢庆
Black people will be celebrating,
而白人也觉得…老实说
white people will be feeling, let's be honest,
良心会遭受谴责
a little conscious-stricken.
我们认为这是你这本书的大好契机
We think it's going to be a huge moment for your book.
斯塔格 你开心吗?
So, Stagg, are you so, so happy?
我们觉得很赞 约翰 真的
We think it's great, John, really.
太不可思议了
Amazing.
真的很棒
Yeah, it's, uh...It's great.
我有个想法
And, you know, I've got an idea
想跟你们两位分享
I want to share with you two.
好啊 我们很喜欢听好点子
Oh, well, I mean, we always love to hear great ideas.
好啊 酷  -好的
Oh, yeah, cool.  -Yeah.
我想改书名
I want to change the title.
我不想…  -老实说
I don't...  -Okay. Um, well, just to be clear,
我们很喜欢《我有病》这个书名
we really do love My Pafology.
超爱  -他有种欧文威尔许
Love it. It's got that whole Irvine Welsh
无产阶级白话的感觉  -对
proletarian vernacular thing.  -Yeah.
所以我才会认为
No, and that's why I think
你们会更喜欢我的新书名
you're going to love this new title even more.
好 我们一直都
Well, okay, you know what,
很乐意听新的想法
we're always happy to hear new ideas.
你的想法是什么呢?   -《操》
What did you have in mind? Fuck.
抱歉 什么?
I'm sorry. Pardon me.
《操》
Fuck.
我想把书名改成《操》
I want to call it Fuck.
你在干什么?   -搞死这些蠢蛋
What are you doing?  -Screw these idiots.
住手  -不要
Stop it.  -No.
斯塔格 如果改成《靠》呢?
So, Stagg, what about, uh, like, Damn?
《靠》? 或《妈的》?
Mm-hm.  -Damn? Or Hell?
不要 我只想要《操》
Nah. Fuck.
好 很好
Okay, that's cool. Uh...
但也许我们可以写成《甘》
But maybe we could do that with a PH instead
因为这样读者的接受度…  -好
because that would be more palatable... Yes. Yes.
比较高  -我不想管这些
...to our sellers. I don't care about all that.
若你们不改书名  我就不把版权给你们了
And if you don't change the title, the deal is off.
哇 不行  -我们不要这么着急
Oh, yeah. No.  -Whoa, whoa, whoa. There's no need to be hasty.  -No, no, no.
这样吧
You know what?
给我们一点时间
Why don't we--Juts give us a second
我们等一下再回复你 好吗?
and, um, a moment and we will get right back to you, okay?
你在干什么?   -你又在干什么? 这太蠢了
What are you doing? What are you doing? This is ridiculous.
你知道这有多少钱吗?
Do you know how much money we're talking about?
我不管 我要终止这件事
I don't care, I'm shutting it down.
终止这件事  -别这样
Shutting it--Come on.  -Shutting it down.
你还在吗?   -拜托…
Are you there?  -Please, just...
我们还在
We're here.
就这么做吧
Let's do it.
什么?   -什么?
What?  -What?
对 我们讨论完了
Yeah. We discussed it,
我们认为这书名太棒适合了
and we think it is very in your face in the best way possible.
这实在非常…
It is very, uh...
黑?
Black?
就是这样 没错
That's it. Yes, that's it.
我很高兴是你这么说 而不是我
I'm happy you said it, and not me.
靠
Oh, fuck.
真的太棒了 斯塔格
It's fucking great, Stagg.  -I love it. Yes.  -Oh, my...
太勇敢了 真的
You know, it's so brave actually.
我好累  -我也是
I'm exhausted. Yeah, me too.
我还得再熬夜几小时读这些书…
I got to stay up a few more hours reading these books for...
嘿
Hey.
Hey. Hey!
老兄
Bro.
该死
Oh, shit.
你在这里干什么?
What are you doing here?
我在这里干什么?   你又在这里干什么?
What am I doing here?  -What are you doing here?
什么我在这里干什么? 你怎么会来?
What do you mean, what am I doing? Why are you in town?
我来看妈
I came to see our mother.
这不就是你这几周打给我的原因?
Ain't that what you been calling me about for weeks now?
你的眼睛怎么了?   -我打架了
What happened to your eye? I got into a fight.  -Yeah.
给我滚出泳池
Well, get out of the pool.
你真是一团乱  -我不想出泳池
You're making a mess.  -I don't want to get out of the pool.
我是个大人了 这是你女友吗?
I'm a grown-ass man. This your girlfriend?
对 你吓到她了
Yeah, you scared the shit out of her.
我是卡罗琳
I'm Coraline.
嗨 卡罗琳
Hi, Coraline.
至少她不是白人
At least she's not white again.
你老婆是白人
Your wife was white.
我老婆是个幌子 那不算数
My wife was a beard. Beards don't count.
出来 你这混账
Well, get out. You fucking menace.
你会吵醒邻居的  -去他妈的邻居
You'll wake the neighbors. You know, fuck your neighbors!
去他妈的干净游泳池
And fuck your clean pool!
那只是你的优越感作祟
It's all just a part of your superiority complex, anyway.
该死的混蛋
Fucking asshole.
你真是他妈的幼稚
You are a goddamn child!
这个时机说可能不太好  但我刚尿在你泳池里
It's probably a bad time to tell you, but I did piss down there.
靠
Fuck.
很好笑吧?
Oh, funny, huh?
抱歉了 莫克
I'm sorry, Monk.
别生气
Don't get mad.
给我滚出去
Get out of here.
你想揍我吗?
You want a piece of me?
很好笑吗?
It's funny, huh?
我一丝不挂地跟他躺在床上
So I'm lying in bed with him, butt-ass naked
克劳德拿着酸奶冰琪淋走进来
and in walks Claude carrying the frozen yogurt.
不会吧  -对 我忘记我有告诉他
No.  -Yeah, I forgot I'd shown him
备用钥匙放在哪里
where I keep the spare key.
所以他朝我们丢酸奶
So he just throws the yogurt at us
然后给我眼睛一拳
and then he wallops me right in the eye.
另一个家伙在干什么?
What was the other guy doing?
他忍不住一直笑
He couldn't stop laughing.
他说他紧张的时候就会笑
He said that's what he does when he gets nervous.
好吧
Okay.
你最近真的放很开
You really going for it these days.
我才变成男同志不久  我得弥补过去浪费的时间
I only been gay for, like, five minutes, I got to make up for lost time.
很棒
Yeah. Well, good for you.
这个世界都要毁了
I mean, the whole world's falling apart.
还不如找点乐子
Might as well have some fun.
很高兴你这么说  -对啊
I appreciate that.  -Yeah.
你真的很美
You know, you're quite beautiful.
谢谢
Thank you.
你到底看上我哥哪点?
What do you see in my brother?
他很好笑
He's funny.  -Mm.
他才不好笑  -不是那种笑出来的好笑
He's not funny. No.  -No, not ha-ha funny.
不是  -是那种带点悲伤的好笑
Like, sad funny.  -Okay.
了解  -像是只有三只脚的狗
Like a three-legged dog.
我懂了 像是死在马桶上的人
I see it now. Like somebody dying on a toilet.
没错
Exactly.
你每次都很过分
Exactly.  -Invariably, you go too far.
是吗? 我觉得我还不够过分
You think? I don't think I go far enough.
变得有点伤人了
It's becoming hurtful.
看吧
Aw.  -See? See?  -"You know,
"你每次都很过分"
invariably..."  -Oh. "...you go too far."
没事啦
Yeah.
你得到了一个吻 很棒吧
You got a kiss, man. Look at you.
只要装可怜就好 上天保佑
Just by being pathetic. God bless you.  -Hey.
装可怜就像三只脚的狗
That is likea three-legged dog.  -Hey.
真不错
Oh, this is nice.
还不差呢
Yeah, it's not bad.
那是什么 藤蔓凉亭吗?
What do you got there, pergola?
只是一般凉亭而已
No, that's a gazebo.
差不多啦
Same difference.
往右转吗?   -往左
All right?  -To the left.
借过
Oh. Excuse me.
嘿 莫克?
Hey, Monk?
你怎么付得起这个地方?
How the hell can you afford this place?
我…
I, um...
莉莎有留点钱给妈
Well, there was some money Lisa left for Mother.
我以为离婚让她钱都没了
Thought the divorce cleaned her out.
我不清楚她的财务状况
Well, I'm not familiar with what her finances were like,
但若你对费用有兴趣
but if you're so interested in the bills,
也许我可以把账单寄给你?
perhaps I can start sending them to you?
不用了 我们要去哪里?   -这边 44号房
Ah, it's fine. Where we going? Right here. 44.
惊喜！
Surprise!
我们今天早上不太顺利
We've had a difficult morning.
她在试图攻击护理师后  我们得给她镇定剂
We had to sedate her after she tried to strike a nurse.
她以前有这样过吗?   -没有
Has she done that before?  -No.
她每天的状况都不一样
She has a different demeanor every day.
有时候每小时就变一次
Sometimes every hour.
但也许她明天会感觉好一些
But maybe she'll feel better tomorrow.
很抱歉 我得走了  -没问题 谢谢
I'm sorry, I need to go. Yes, of course. Thank you.
这是园丁剪下要送给你妈的
The gardener cut these right off the bush for your mom.
很贴心吧?   -对啊 很棒
Sweet, right?  -Yeah, that's great.
你是怎么负担这边的费用?
How can you afford this place?
你没有贩毒之类的吧?
I mean, you're not a drug dealer or something, are you?
没有 我是作家
No, I'm a writer.
你是我女友 不是我的簿记员
And you're my girlfriend, not my bookkeeper.
Down a mountain
Do it with my bare hands
I crush the rocks to stone
And toss them up to heaven
The moment I was blue
I'd rush right home to you
If all these things I do for you
I would write a symphony...
我一直都知道你不是男同志
I always knew you weren't a queer.
One that would make...
It would be a melody...
她不知道她在说什么  -我要去外面等
She doesn't know what she's saying. I'm going to wait outside.
Make a notion
To search out my devotion
We didn't go Hand in hand...
你确定你不想留下来  参加罗蓝的婚礼?
You sure you don't want to stay for Lorraine's wedding?
我还是离开比较好
It's better if I go.
很高兴认识你 克里夫
It was nice to meet you, Cliff.
这个家真的很伤人的心
This family will break your heart.
肯尼娅
肯尼娅·达斯汀秀
欢迎回来 我是肯尼娅·达斯汀
Welcome back. I'm Kenya Dunston
今天我们要讨论一本新小说
and today, we're going to discuss
它刚登上《纽约时报》
a new novel that just debuted at number one
畅销书排行榜第一名
on The New York Times bestseller list.
这是本很杰出又特别的书
It is just a remarkable, special book,
书名是
and it's called...
快把小孩的眼耳遮起来
Cover your kids' eyes and ears...
斯塔格·R·利亚
我们今天很荣幸请到作者上节目
We are lucky enough to have the author with us today.
对于刚收看的观众
And for those of you who are just joining us,
请理解斯塔格·R·利亚先生的  访问所在地
please know that Mr. Stagg R. Leigh is coming to us
必须保持秘密
from an undisclosed location
因为他是位在逃通缉犯
as he is still on the run from authorities.
通缉犯暨作者 斯塔格·R·利亚
斯塔格 请告诉我们  这本小说是改编自真实故事吗?
Oh, Stagg, tell us, is this novel a true story?
其实不然
Not factually,
但对于像我这样的美国黑人
but it's the true story of what it's like
它与真实故事十分相近
to be a Black man in America like me.
不太光彩
And it ain't pretty.
阿门
Amen to that.
在我服刑期间
During my time in prison,
每个人的嘴上都挂着这个字
I learned that words belong to everybody.
所以这本书  要献给我们这个美丽的国家
So this book is my contribution to this wonderful country of ours
它让前科犯也能致富
where a Black ex-con can become rich
只要透过讲述
simply by telling the story
那些不幸同胞的故事
of his unfortunate people.
没错
Yes. Yes.
阿瑟来电 接受、拒绝
怎么了  -告诉你
Yeah.  -Get this.
联邦调查局今天打给汤普森·瓦特
The FBI called Thompson Watt today
想得知斯塔格·R·利亚的真实身份
to try to get Stagg R. Leigh's identity.
什么?   -别担心
What?  -Don't worry.
他们不会放弃的
They're not going to give him up.
放弃什么? 那就是我 我什么都没做
Give who up? It's me, I haven't done anything.
他们又不知道  -听着 这事玩过火了
They don't know that. Look, this has gone too far.
放心
Relax.
通缉犯这件事  让我们得到许多媒体关注
The fugitive stuff's getting us mountains of free press.
加上 如你所说 你什么都没做
Plus, as you said, you haven't done anything.
他们又不能逮捕你
It's not like they can arrest you.
真希望我当初没有卖这本书
I wish I could go back to not selling books.
我可不这么认为
I don't.
再见
Bye.
一切都还好吧?
Is everything all right?
还好
Yeah.
我只是压力有点大
I'm just a little stressed out. This, uh.
文学奖的工作比我想象中还繁重
book award stuff is a bit more work than I expected.
可恶
Shit.
没关系 再去厨房拿一些叉子就好
It's no biggie. Got more forks in the kitchen.
这是什么?   -我朋友给我的
What's this? Mm. My friend got it for me.
你读了吗?   -当然还没 你呢?
Have you read it? Of course not, have you?
读了
Yeah.
《操》
你觉得如何?
And what did you think of it?
我很喜欢  -为什么喜欢?
I liked it.  -What did you like about it?
它没冒犯到你吗?
Um...  -It didn't offend you?
你不是说你还没读吗? 怎么了?
You just said you didn't read it. What's your problem?
不 回答我的问题
No, you answer my question.
你才回答我的问题
You answer mine.
我的问题是这种书一点都不真实
My problem is that books like this aren't real.
它简化了我们的人生
They flatten our lives.
什么意思?
What do you mean?
虽然我的生活一团糟
I mean, that... you know, my life is a disaster,
但不是书里描述的这样
but not in the way you'd think reading this shit.
这些东西简化了我们的生命历程
These things reduce us and they do it over
他们却一再这么做  只因为有太多白人
and over again because too many white people,
和你这样的人喜欢这种垃圾
and people apparently like you devour this slop
就像吃馊水的猪
like pigs at a dumpster
或是想在鸡尾酒派对跟上潮流
to stay current at fucking cocktail parties
之类的  -好
or whatever.  -Okay, um...
一个好几年没出书的人意见这么多
You got a lot of opinions for someone who hasn't published anything for years.
而你又出版了什么?
And you've published what exactly?
你到底是有什么问题?
Okay, what is wrong with you?
你为什么要这样?
Why are you acting like this?
我没有怎么样
I'm not acting like anything.
你这几周都怪里怪气的
You've been acting like a weirdo for weeks.
你一直混淆视听、偷偷摸摸
You've been obfuscating, sneaking around.
没人知道你在干什么
You're fucking unknowable.
也许你以为神神秘秘  很潮又很有艺术感
Maybe you think being an enigma is chic and artsy.
那只会让你像个混蛋  -这个嘛
I just think it makes you an asshole. Well, um,
你不懂我的人生 你也没办法
you don't understand my life, and you can't,
所以就不要深究了
so just leave it at that.
也许你有天会了解
One day, maybe you'll learn
无法与他人产生共鸣
that not being able to relate to other people
并不是一件值得荣耀的事
isn't a badge of honor.
我觉得你该离开了
I think you should leave.
你知道我怎么想的吗?
Well, you know what I think?
你该离开了 莫克
You should leave, Monk.
乱写一通
Nonsense.
你们需要帮忙吗?
You guys need any help with that?
不用 我们没问题
Nah, we're good.
我以为你们需要帮忙
I thought you could use a little brawn.
我们自己来就好了
We got it.
莫克先生 你介意  把气泡水制造机给我吗?
Mr. Monk. You mind I keep the soda maker?
反正你也不喜欢气泡水 对吧?
You don't like the bubbly water anyhow, right?
送你吧  -谢谢
It's all yours.  -Thank you.
嘿 那这个呢?
Um... Hey, what about this?
不要 一直都很讨厌那个颜色
No. I always hated that color.
那是你爸买的
It's just the one your father bought.
塞洛尼斯 你的包裹
Thelonious, this just came for you.
好的 谢谢
Okay, thanks.
这是最后一批了
This is the last of it.
再会了 莫克先生
Goodbye, Mr. Monk.
再见 罗兰
Bye, Lorraine.
开车小心
Drive safe.
我们婚礼见  -好的
Guess I'll see you at the wedding. All right.
我来拿
I'll take that there.
我们很乐意提名这本书  参加文学奖评选
显然汤普森·瓦特  希望能赶快出版这本书
Thompson Watt apparently raced to publish it.
我听说他们已经印了30万册
Yeah, I heard that they ran 300,000 copies already
很快又要再刷
and they're reprinting more soon.
这本书势如破竹
I mean, it's going like gangbusters .
老天 这本书最好真的那么好看
Christ on a crutch! It better be good.
我听说作者是通缉犯
Hey, I heard the writer's a fugitive.
这样就能解释书名了
Well, that would explain the title.
他可没受过文化洗礼
He didn't go to charm school.
我认为那样的背景很加分
No, I think that that background is a plus.
我很喜欢读有色人种
I am thrilled to read a BIPOC man harmed
被我们监狱国家欺负的故事
by our carceral state.
你也是那种支持  减少警方资源的疯子吗?
Are you one of those defund the police nuts?
对 但我不期望能得到你的理解
Yes, and I wouldn't expect you to understand.
希望你爱的人不会被强暴或谋杀
Well, I hope someone you love doesn't get raped or murdered.
我们现在可以不要聊这个吗?
Can we not talk about this now, please?
听着
Look, look, look.
无论他是否是罪犯  我们都不该把这本书加进来
Criminal or not, I don't think we should add it.
这个过程已经进行好几周了  我不晓得你们的状况
We're already weeks into the process, and I don't know about any of you,
但我还有十几本书还没读
but I've got more than a dozen books I haven't even opened yet.
这本书在缴交日期前就出版了
It was published before the submission date,
我认为我们应该要收这本书
I think we have to accept it.
只是多一本书而已
Yeah, it's just one more.
而且看样子 这本书很快就读完了
And from the looks of it, it should be a quick read.
像是一场性爱快餐
A quick fuck.
我有过几次这样的经验
I've had a couple of those.
我要挂电话了 再见
Bye, guys. Bye.
嗨 小亲亲
Hi, Monkie.
你好美
You look beautiful.
你好
Oh, hello.
小亲亲 我们认识这些人吗?
Monkie, do we know these men?
不 妈 这些人不是幻觉  他们是真的陌生人
No, Mother, this isn't the Alzheimer's, these are actual strangers.
你们是谁?   -我们是克里夫的朋友
Who are you people? We're Cliff's friends.
我想也是
Of course, you are.
我们是几天前认识的  我是肯尼 他是艾文
We met him a few days ago. I'm Kenny, this is Alvin.
你是莫克吗?   -是的 你怎么知道?
Are you Monk? I am. How did you know?
克里夫说莫克的屁股很紧实
Oh. Well, Cliff said Monk's a real tight-ass.
是吗? 真开心
Did he? Delightful.
妈 你坐这边
Mother, you sit here.
罗兰?
Lorraine?
你喜欢炒蛋吗?   -我很爱炒蛋
Do you like scrambled eggs? I love scrambled eggs.
你在这里干什么?   -你才是吧
What the hell are you doing here? You first.
靠 婚礼
Oh, shit, the wedding.
靠
Ah.  -Oh, fuck!
我没去机场
I didn't go to the airport.
我离开的那天 我想自己静静
That day I left, I needed some time to myself.
想自己静静表示不想被打扰
Time to oneself implies by definition, time alone.
老天 走吧
Oh, Christ, here we go.
字典侦探
Detective Dictionary.  -Ah!
克里夫先生  -很抱歉 各位 我来处理
Mr. Cliff. I'm sorry, guys, I'll handle it.
你得离开
You need to leave.
别整理了 走吧
Don't bother to clean up, just go.
不 没关系 请留下来
Oh, no, it's all right, just... Please stay.
这是场庆祝
It's a celebration.
很高兴看到你 克里夫
It's good to see you, Cliff.
我也很高兴见到你 米纳
It's good to see you too, Maynard.
我不想强留
I, um...I... I don't want to impose.
不会的
You can't impose.
因为你是我家人
You're family.
好的
Okay.
我…
I'll, uh...
我去整理一下 好吗?
I'll go clean up a bit, yeah?
恭喜你们
Congratulations, you guys.
我们可以做早餐给你们吃吗?
Can we make y'all some breakfast?
我很会做奶昔
I can whip up a killer smoothie
艾文曾在邮轮的奥姆蛋摊位打工
and Alvin used to work the omelet station on a cruise ship.
听起来很棒 谢谢
That sounds lovely. Thank you.
很感谢你让他们留下来  -不会的
It's very kind of you to let them stay.
跟别人的家庭打交道总是比较容易
It's always easier dealing with other people's families than your own.
我很遗憾要通知你 再过几小时后
I regret to inform you that in a couple hours,
这就会变成你的家人
this will be your family.
Let love flow on, baby
Let love be free
I reach for you Honey, yeah
You reach for me
We'll do the things together Only lovers do
Let love flow on, baby
Getting into each other
Let's reunite
And we let Love's vibrations
Lead us all right
We'll do the things together Only lovers do
Let love flow on, baby
你把她气走?
Piss her off?
对
Yeah.
不理她?   -对
Shut her out?  -Yeah.
爸也拒所有人于千里之外
Dad shut everyone out too.
他成天说谎
He lied all the time.
你看他那样做的结果
Look how that turned out.
我这些日子就像爸一样生气
I find myself getting very angry these days like Dad.
"这些日子"?
These days?
我最近不断思考  关于爸死前不知道我是同志这件事
I've been thinking a lot lately about how Dad died not knowing I'm gay.
我想他应该略知一二
I think he suspected it.  -Mm.
也许吧
He may have.
但他不确定
But he didn't know for sure.
他从没了解完整的我
He never knew the entirety of me.
现在他也没机会了
And now he never will.
这让我觉得…
And that makes me...
让我觉得很伤心
It makes me real sad.
若他知道然后拒绝与你往来呢?
Well, what if he had known and rejected you?
至少他拒绝了真正的我
At least he'd be rejecting the real me.
我知道这听起来很疯狂 但是…
I know that sounds crazy,
那会让我松一口气
but there'd be some relief in that.
听起来并没那么疯狂
It doesn't sound so crazy.
人们想要爱你 莫克
People want to love you, Monk.
我不知道他们看上你什么
I personally don't know what they see in you,
但是
but...
他们想要爱你
they want to love you.
你应该让他们爱全部的你
You should let them love all of you.
10《斯卡特》  9《奇怪的工作》
真烂
It was dogshit.
某位娇生惯养的蠢蛋
I mean, some mollycoddled chump
不断喋喋不休关于他死去的妈妈
faffing on about his dead mom...
有谁在乎啊?
Who cares?
这表示《站着被埋葬》第四名
Okay, so that means that Bury Me Standing is fourth.
我们来谈谈《操》吧
Let's talk about Fuck.
可以不要吗?
Could we not?
我很喜欢
Personally, I adored it.
这就像是在直视伤口
It was like gazing into an open wound.
我同意  我认为这是我很长一段时间
I agree. I think it's the strongest African-American novel
读过最强的非裔美国人小说
I've read in a long time.
但当然是读了你的书后
I mean, since yours.
无庸置疑 辛塔拉  -谢谢
Of course, Sintara.  -Thank you.
我其实比我想象中还喜欢这本书
You know, I actually liked it much more than I was expecting.
这是部勇敢的作品
I mean, this is a gutsy piece of work.
是当代不可或缺的作品
And necessary for the times.
你觉得呢 辛塔拉
What did you think, Sintara?
我觉得它刻意迎合读者口味
I found it to be pretty pandering, actually.
真的吗?
You did?
对啊 你没发现吗?
Yes. Did you not?
我有发现
I very much did.
我认为它太过简化且无意义
I thought it was simplistic and meaningless.
它当然很简化
Well, of course, it was simplistic.
毕竟那是贫民区的语言
I mean, it's the language of the gutter.
不是什么谨慎的研究所论文
You know, not some prissy graduate thesis.
"贫民区的语言" 老天
"Language of the gutter." Jesus Christ.
我觉得我们都累了
I think our blood sugar's low.
何不休息吃个午餐?
How about we take a break for lunch, huh?
可以  -好
Fine by me.  -Okay.
太好了
Okay.  -Really?
好
Okay.
噢 抱歉  -没关系
Oh, I'm sorry. Oh, no, you're fine.
我没打扰你吧?   -没有
What, I'm not interrupting? No.
《白黑鬼》
抱歉
Sorry.
你介意我问你问题吗?
Do you mind if I ask you something?
不会
Sure.
你觉得《操》在哪个部分迎合读者?
What about Fuck did you find pandering?
我很难直接指出是什么 但是…
I can't really put my finger on it, but...
但它跟市面上其他一些小说无异
it's not different from some of what's out there,
但就是有种…
but it just felt...
没有灵魂的感觉
soulless...
我只能想到这种形容方式
is the word that I'm going to use.
你说你也同意 对吧?
You said you agreed, right?
对 我认为它看起来
Yeah, I do. I think it seems written
是用来迎合有罪恶感的白人读者
to satisfy the tastes of guilt-ridden white people.
对 那种书评称之为
Yeah, the kind of book critics call important
"重要"和"必要"  而非"好作品"的书
and necessary, but not well-written.
没错
Exactly.
好 请你不要感到被冒犯
Okay, so... And please don't take offense at this,
但《操》跟你的书差别在哪里?
but how is Fuck so very different from your book?
这就是你真正想谈的事吗?
Is that what this is about?
你认为我的书很垃圾?   -不
You think my book's trash?  -No.
老实说 我还没读过你的书
To be honest, I haven't read your book.
我有读过片段 但我看不出来
I've read excerpts and it didn't seem
差别在哪里
so dissimilar.
我为了我的书做了许多研究
I did a lot of research for my book.
有些是直接来自真正的访问
Some of it was actually taken from real interviews.
也许你在学术象牙塔待太久了
Maybe you've been up in your ivory tower of academia for so long
你已经忘记人们的生活有多辛苦
you've forgotten that some people's lives are hard.
那你呢?
Your life?
你上了特别的艺术大学
You went to an exclusive bohemian college.
你在纽约的高级出版社工作
You had a job at a fancy publishing house in New York.
又怎样? 我不需要写我的生活
So what? I don't need to write about my life.
我写人们有兴趣的事
I write about what interests people.
你写的是白人出版社感兴趣  打击黑人创伤的煽情内容
You write what interests white publishers fiending Black trauma porn.
毕竟他们才是买家
They're the one buying the manuscripts.
迎合他们的口味很糟糕吗?
Is it bad to cater to their tastes?
若你愿意迎合人们的欲望以获益
If you're okay feeding people's base desires for profit--
我也认为迎合市场没有问题
I'm okay with giving the market what it wants.
这就是毒贩为自己找的借口
That's how drug dealers excuse themselves.
我认为毒品应该要合法化
And I think drugs should be legal.
但你不觉得受够了吗?
But you're not fed up with it?
贫穷的黑人?
You know, Black people in poverty?
饶舌的黑人?
Black people rapping?
为奴的黑人?
Black people as slaves?
黑人被警察谋杀?
Black people murdered by the police?
各种煽情的文章  -够了
Old soaring narratives about... Okay.
关于悲惨的黑人
Black folks in dire circumstances
直到死前都仍在奋斗保卫尊严
who still managed to maintain their dignity before they die?
我不是说这些事情都是假的
I mean, I'm not saying these things aren't real,
但我们其实不只如此
but we're also more than this.
所以像你这样的作者们
And it's like so many writers like you can't envision us
不能让白人掐着脖子创作
without some white boot on our necks.
你会生气布雷特·伊斯顿·艾利斯  或查理·布考斯基
Do you get angry at Bret Easton Ellis or Charles Bukowski
写了受压迫者的文章
for writing about the downtrodden?
还是你只对黑人女性愤怒?
Or is your ire strictly reserved for Black women?
没人读布考斯基后认为
Nobody reads Bukowski thinking
他就代表了白人经验
his is the definitive white experience.
但人们 特别是白人  读了你的书就认定我们就是如此
But people, white people, read your book and confine us to it.
他们认为我们都是那样
They think that we're all like that.
那莫克 这似乎是
Then it sounds like your issue
你与白人间的问题 而不是我
is with white people, Monk, not me.
也许吧 但我也想到这个国家中
Well, maybe, but I also think that I see the unrealized potential
那些还没成功却有潜力的黑人
of Black people in this country.
"有潜力"正代表人们认为
Potential is what people see when they think
这些人目前的处境并不够好
what's in front of them isn't good enough.
在讨论什么呢?
So, what are we talking about?
卡罗琳
我很抱歉
我想跟你说一些事
你是否愿意跟我去参加  下周的文学奖颁奖典礼?
我们又要开始了
We're starting again.
我马上过去
I'll be right there.
阿瑟在吗? 对 我是莫克
Hey, can I speak to Arthur? Yeah, it's Monk.
嘿 我没事
Hey. I'm fine.
你可以帮我安排和瓦利  再见一次面吗?
Listen, you think you can set up another meeting with Wiley?
我有些新想法
I've got a new idea for him.
关于另一种电影 谢啦
Different kind of movie. Thanks.
我想选《操》
I think it's Fuck for me.
我也是  -我同意
Yeah, me too.  -Yeah, I agree.
我不同意 抱歉
I disagree. I'm sorry.
我认为给这本书奖项是个错误
I think it would be a mistake to award this book anything.
票数是二比三 所以…
Well, it's two versus three, so...
《操》是赢家
Fuck's the winner.
Fuck is the winner.
我认为这本书不只是撼动人心
You know, it's not just that it's so affecting,
我也认为聆听黑人的心声是很重要的
I just think it's essential to listen to Black voices right now.
妈
Mother.
你知道…
Did you...
你知道爸背着你偷情吗?
Did you know that Dad was cheating on you?
他很不会守密
He was bad at keeping secrets.
你为何不离开他?
Why didn't you leave him?
他没有我会更寂寞
He would've been even more lonely without me.
你认为他很寂寞?
You thought he was lonely?
你爸是个天才
You father was a genius.
天才都很寂寞
Geniuses are lonely...
因为他们无法和我们产生连结
because they can't connect with the rest of us.
你也是个天才 儿子
You're a genius, son.
但我大多时间却没有这样的感受
Well, I certainly don't feel like one half the time.
因为你对自己太严格了 克里夫
That's because you've always been so hard on yourself, Cliffy.
现在是今晚最后一个奖项
And now for the final award for the evening.
我发誓颁完后  会让你们去吃晚餐
I promise to leave you alone, let you eat after this.
但在我宣布赢家之前
But before I announce the winner,
我想要向评审们致敬
I would like to acknowledge our judges,
这些是我们多元的评审
our incredibly diverse group of judges
他们牺牲了宝贵的时间  让我们在此共襄盛举
who've sacrificed valuable time, so we could all celebrate here tonight.
替他们鼓掌吧 他们非常了不起
So if you put your hands together, they did a fantastic job.
好的
Okay.
别再拖延
Without further ado,
今年的文学奖得主是
this year's Literary Award goes to...
我就知道
Oh, I knew it.
斯塔格·R·利亚的《操》
By Stagg R. Leigh, Fuck.
我不确定利亚先生
Well, I'm not sure if Mr. Leigh is going to grace us
会在今晚现身
with his presence here tonight.
他对关注度非常敏感
He's notoriously cagey about attention.
等等
Oh, hold on.
有些动静
Oh, okay. I see some business.
有人来了
Someone's coming. Oh, Thelonious Ellison.
我们卓越的评审之一
One of our esteemed judges.
他诡异地朝舞台走来
Weirdly walking toward the stage.
不知道原因
No idea why.
嘿 怎么了?
Hey. What's going on?
抱歉
Excuse me.
不好意思
我想坦承一件事
I have a confession to make.
等等 画面一片黑?
Wait, wait, wait. Smash to black?
不行啦 老兄
No fucking way, dude.
这样有什么不好?
What's wrong with that?
问题没有解决啊 他要说什么?
There's no resolution here. What's he going to say?
我不知道
I don't know.
这才是有趣之处
I think that's what's interesting about it.
不 他应该说些什么 你说了什么?
No, he should say something. What did you say?
我什么都没说 我走出典礼
Nothing. I walked out of the ceremony.
隔天我打给你说我想创作这部电影
The next day I called you to say I wanted to write this movie.
莫克 那个角色得说些什么
Well, Monk, the character should say something.
我不希望他说些什么冠冕堂皇的话
Well, I don't want him to make some grandiose speech spoon-feeding everyone
告诉大家这个故事的寓意
the moral of the story.
这个故事没有寓意 这才是重点
There is no moral. That's the idea.
我喜欢模糊的感觉
I like the ambiguity.
听着 你是个好编剧  但电影就快结束了
Okay, look. You're a good writer, and this is almost there.
但小说不是电影 好吗?
But novels aren't movies, okay?
模糊不会换来更多票房
Nuance doesn't put asses in theater seats.
我们需要一个大结局 这是什么?
We need a big finish. What is this?
这是你要的气泡水
It's the seltzer you asked for.
为什么这是湿的?
Why is it all wet?
冷凝现象?
Condensation?
冷凝现象 好吧
Condensation. Okay.
你现在是自然大师了吗?
You're a fucking weatherman now.
你想来点什么吗?   -不用了 谢谢
You want anything? Uh, no, I'm fine. Thank you.
好 这是莫克  我们要跟他创作一部电影
All right. This is Monk. We're going to make a movie with him
若他能把第三幕写好
if he can get the third act right.
很高兴见到你  -我也是
Nice meeting you. You as well.
给我白开水就好 不要再湿了
Get me a flat white. And, hey, never again.
好的
All right.
你脑中还有什么结局?
What other endings you got in that big brain of yours?
那这样如何…
How about if...
今年的文学奖得主是
This year's Literary Award goes to...
斯塔格·R·利亚的《操》
by Stagg R. Leigh, Fuck.
我想道歉
I'd like to apologize.
我最近不太对劲
I haven't been myself lately.
这样如何?
What about that?
她会原谅他吗?
Will she forgive him?
我不知道
I don't know.
现实世界的卡罗琳不回我电话
The real Coraline won't return my phone calls.
也许电影里的卡罗琳比较宽容
Maybe the movie Coraline is more forgiving.
不行 那样太美好了
No. It's too pat.
让这整部电影变成浪漫喜剧
Makes the whole thing feel like a romantic comedy.
我们不是要拍浪漫喜剧
We don't want to make a romantic comedy.
我们要拍真实的电影
We want to make something real.
给我点真实一点的结局
Give me something real.
那我们也可以…
I mean, we could just...
嘿 怎么了?
Hey, what's going on?
抱歉
Excuse me.
滚
Beat it.
我想坦白一件事
I have a confession to make.
斯塔格·R·利亚 趴下来
Stagg Leigh, on the ground now!
他在那里
There he is!
不 我不是斯塔格·R·利亚 他不存在
No, no. I'm not Stagg Leigh. He doesn't exist.
我是莫克 塞洛尼斯·艾里森
I'm Monk. Thelonious Ellison.
你是通缉犯 给我趴在地上
You're a fugitive! On the ground now!
不是的
No, no, no.
这都只是营销手法
That was all a marketing gimmick.
这全是个谎言
It was all a lie.  -He's got a gun!
他有拿枪  -不
No, no! No, no!
他死了吗?
He's dead?
警察把他干掉了?
They smoke him?
太完美了
It's perfect.
太好了
Yes!
这实在是
That is...
太完美了
That is perfect.
该挑件礼服了 老兄
Time to pick out your tux, my brother.
这部电影一定会卖座的
We're going to the big show.
过来抄写 我们完成了
Hey, come transcribe this. We got it.
靠
Fuck.
嘿
Hey.
所以呢?
So?
他们要拍你的电影吗?
They going to make your movie or what?
很不幸的 是的
Unfortunately, yes.
嘿
Hey! You know what?
这样的话 你最好找个够帅的人
Good luck finding someone handsome enough
来扮演我
to play me.
他们已经找到了
I think they have.
他们找谁?
Who they got?
泰勒·派瑞
Tyler Perry.
正合我意 太棒了
You got me. That's good.
好的
All right.
改编自小说《擦除》  珀西瓦尔·埃弗雷特所著